<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[303]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[What you need to know about summer sleep in Alaska - AKRDY]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Living in Alaska has its perks, especially in the summer. Unfortunately, one of those summer perks also comes with a summer drawback, getting a good night’s sleep in the land of the Midnight Sun.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It’s true, most of Alaska receives almost 20 hours of daylight in the summer. The summer sunlight begins to ramp up in May and starts to taper off by the end of August. The far north of Alaska receives almost two consecutive months of total daylight in the summer while other parts of Alaska, for instance, along the Kenai Peninsula, see closer to 19 hours of daylight. Even though most of Alaska, see the sunset in the summer, Alaska doesn’t see full dark. Instead, Alaska receives what is known as civil twilight (or just twilight) for about two to three hours for most of the summer months. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":304,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alarm-clock-1193291_640.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-304"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Near constant daylight sounds like a great idea, until you check your phone or your watch and realize it’s 0200 and the sun has started to set. No wonder you’re tired!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Summer sleep in Alaska may not be an easy adjustment for even the most seasoned military family, so we’ve compiled some helpful tips and supplies you may need to make the transition easier.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Make time for winding down and relaxing</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It’s tempting to give in to the extra daylight and fish a little bit longer or plant one more row in the garden, but it won’t help you fall asleep. Your body and mind need time to unwind and prepare for sleep. There are several activities you can do to quiet your mind and your body.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Read a book</li><li>Listen to soothing music.</li><li>Meditate</li><li>Take a warm bath or shower</li><li>Write in a journal or write out tomorrow’s to-do list.</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the best things you can do to relax is to turn off your devices 30 to 60 minutes before bedtime. If you typically use a tablet or smartphone for reading or listening to music, make sure the blue light filter is on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Create the proper sleep environment</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To go to sleep, your body and mind must agree that it’s time to sleep. The right sleep environment can make all the difference in how your body relaxes. The more relaxed your body is, the easier it may be to fall asleep.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Simple things like turning down the thermostat or having an aromatherapy diffuser can help set the scene for good sleep.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Your room should be a quiet, comfortable space for sleeping. Some people find a sleep machine, white noise machine, or other sounds such as crickets, owls, frogs, even thunderstorms, (all things you might hear at night in the lower 48), help lull you to sleep as you adjust to Alaska’s unique summer.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":305,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sunset-888893_640.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-305"/><figcaption>Sunset on Cook Inlet</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Investing in darkening curtains or darkening blinds is one thing all Alaskans swear by to get a good night’s sleep. Darkening curtains (or blackout curtains as most Alaskans call them) aren’t only for bedrooms. Most homes in Alaska have some type of curtains or blinds in the main rooms of the house that are easy to open and close and help filter light depending on the time of day. Blackout curtains are typically used in bedrooms because they are usually made from heavier material or are lined for extra light reduction (also helpful in keeping the bedroom a lower temperature). If you’re exceptionally light-sensitive, you may also want to consider a sleep mask.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Consider using supplements</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Living in Alaska can mess with your body’s natural production of hormones such as vitamin D and melatonin. When the sun sets, your body produces melatonin to trigger sleep before bed. The body’s production of melatonin helps keep your circadian rhythm in check.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Unfortunately, Alaska’s near-constant sunlight in the summer interrupts this process and can result in poor sleep, a disrupted sleep cycle, or sleep deprivation. Our bodies need the melatonin production to keep our sleep cycles intact. To counteract this, many Alaskans enlist the help of melatonin to aid in sleep, especially during the transition from winter to summer.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>(Consult your physician or a sleep specialist before taking any supplements)</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Maintain a normal eating schedule</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One thing that easily gets thrown off balance during Alaska summers are eating schedules. Until you’ve adjusted to summer in Alaska, you’ll want to keep your meal schedule as close to normal as you did before arriving in Alaska.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Of course, it’s important to listen to your body’s natural cues to hunger but because of the extensive daylight, it’s not uncommon to spend a day in the Alaska sunshine only to realize you haven’t had dinner yet. A quick glance at the time and you may be surprised to realize it’s nearly 2300! Eating too close to bedtime can disrupt your sleep and can severely impact your health.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":306,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-3746812_640.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-306"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you don’t already, you will soon love summer in Alaska. Taking proper care and setting yourself up with the proper tools and schedule for a good night’s rest will make for more fun on the last frontier.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[Getting sleep in Alaska can be a struggle but it doesn't have to be. Use this guide to build a strategy for a better's night sleep today. ]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-05 06:52:55]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-summer-sleep-in-alaska/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alarm-clock-1193291_640.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sunset-888893_640.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-3746812_640.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[alarm-clock-1193291_640.jpg|sunset-888893_640.jpg|alaska-3746812_640.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alarm-clock-1193291_640.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sunset-888893_640.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-3746812_640.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[304|305|306]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[alarm-clock-1193291_640|sunset-888893_640|alaska-3746812_640]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Medical>Sleep Hygiene]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[Alaska|Alaska Summer|Insomnia|Midnight Sun|Sleep]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Nichole]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Smith]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[hello@nicholelsmith.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[nicholelsmith.com]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[310]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Why Bear Spray is Important – Bear Spray 101, Part 1 – AKRDY]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Bottom Line Up Front (BLUF):</span></strong></a> Bear spray is effective, relatively cheap, and easy for all family members to use.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Full disclosure, I’ve never used bear spray against a bear. Unfortunately, if you spend any time in the Alaskan wilderness, you will come across a bear and may need to defend yourself. Bear spray meets this objective and is easy to learn.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">What is Bear Spray</span></strong></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bear Spray is an aerosolized spray derived from capsaicinoids designed to stop a bear attack on humans. Capsaicinoids are popularly found in chili peppers and other plants of the Capsicum species. In layman’s terms, we’re spraying chili pepper in the bear’s face.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Chili Pepper spray might not sound effective. But when they reduce those peppers to only the ‘heat,’ it causes a violent reaction in the bear. If you’ve eaten a hot pepper, you’ve had a mild version of this reaction. Burning and intense pain in your mouth, watery eyes, and runny nose. Remember, this was when you ate the pepper. Now imagine having those same compounds sprayed into nose and eyes as well.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The result is debilitating for the bear. In addition to the pain, the capsaicinoids overtake the nostrils and eyes, neutralizing the bears’ ability to smell and see. When combined, you can understand why bear spray stops a 1500 lb bear in its tracks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Different Bear Encounter Situations</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color"><strong>Surprise Encounters (High Risk):</strong></span></a> This is what most people think about when discussing bear attacks and for a good reason. A surprise encounter is when you and the bear meet unexpectantly. These meetings will usually occur in densely wooded areas and narrow or overgrown trails. The problem with these encounters is that all parties will be reacting out of shock and muscle memory. Just in case you’re wondering, the human has a distinct disadvantage. Since the bear is faster, more muscular, and has a lot more practice killing. These are the situations that you want to avoid, great for bear spray. Skip ahead to learn how to use bear spray.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Seen from a Distance (Low Risk):</span></strong></a> These are the situations that most people come to Alaska to experience. Bear viewing from a distance is incredible and allows you to experience their world from a safe view. Viewing from afar enables the human to ‘introduce’ themselves to the bear, so there are no surprises. These are low-risk situations because there’s time to react, in a level headed manner. You have time to take pictures or move to a safe place if needed. It also allows time to prepare your defense. &nbsp;</li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Predatory Bears (High Risk):</span></strong></a> Predatory bears fall outside normal bear behavior for most black and brown bears. These are bears that are initially scared off by human presence but will continually come back. They purposefully hunt humans to kill or consume. There might be multiple reasons they come back, but each reoccurrence is a potential threat to both human and bear. These are high-risk situations because when the bear returns, it’ll require you to either use more bear spray or shot the bear. Eventually, you will either get back to your car, run out of the bear spray, kill the bear, or die.&nbsp;</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Do You Need Bear Spray?</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Based on the numbers alone, your odds of getting attacked by a bear are very low. From 1880-2015 bear attacks averaged only 2.6/year in Alaska (Smith et al., 2018). Compared to the number of visitors, hunters, and anglers that venture into bear territory, your odds are good. These bear attack deaths aren’t trivial. The risk of not bringing bear spray is death. In Russia, where half the world’s Brown bears are, the numbers are only slightly higher at four injuries or deaths per year (Kudrenko et al., 2020).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ll cover preparation in the section on using the bear spray, but we know that certain circumstances and time of year are riskier. High-risk months are from Aug-Oct, Brown bears are more prone to attack then black bears. Additionally, hunters have a higher rate of being attacked than groups of two or more.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you can plan accordingly, stay in big groups, and stay on well-traveled areas, you probably don’t need to bear spray. Ultimately, your choice. To quote the Hunger Games, “May the odds ever be in your favor.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Bear Spray vs. A Gun</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In Alaska, having a gun in the wilderness is a staple. For some, it’s the bravado of gun ownership that drives their decision. For others, the lethality of the weapon gives it the upper hand. This thought is understandable. A gun is far more accurate, has longer range, and deadlier then bear spray. But in practicality, bringing a gun comes down to training.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you trained to use a gun correctly? Let me give you a scenario. You’ve decided to hike along one of the many trails on the Turnagain arm. It’s a beautiful day, a little cold, but perfect for hiking. You’ve been hiking for about two hours. You round a corner where the trail crosses over one of the many creek crossings. As you make the corner, you ask your hiking partner what they’d like to get for dinner on the way home. The trail is a little overgrown in this section. You look up and see a black bear with cubs in the middle of the trail about 40 feet from you. Momma bear is startled and starts to charge. For a startled bear, closing a 40 ft gap will only take a couple of seconds.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>How Comfortable are you with a gun? </h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Do you feel comfortable enough with a gun to draw, aim, and shoot effectively in this situation? If yes, then great. Most people would not, a better way of saying this is most people are not prepared, and this is where the bear spray comes in. It doesn’t take very long to learn how to use bear spray effectively. Shooting a gun does take time and practice.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some activities may lead to using a gun more than others. For example, if you’re hunting, then you’re likely to have your gun at the ready. You’ll also be more vigilant of your surroundings and more likely to have practiced shooting the gun. Unfortunately, hunting comes with higher risk of getting attacked. Probably since you’re not making noise, hard to see, and appear a threat. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Using a gun for defense against bears also makes multiple assumptions. The assumptions are you have the money to purchase a firearm. For a bear gun, it’ll cost about ten times the cost of bear spray, $500-$1000. It also assumes you have the storage for the weapon and a good holster for carrying the gun in the woods. Finally, it assumes you have the time to learn to use it correctly.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">The Research</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This last assumption is the most critical and is what is supported by research. In a review of 269 bear incidents in Alaska from 1883-2009, Smith et al. (2012) found that “…only those proficient in firearms should rely on them for protection in bear country.” The reason for this is when they reviewed these incidents, “…firearm bearers suffered the same injury rates in close encounters with bears whether they used their firearms or not” (Smith et al., 2012). In case you missed this point, for most people having a gun is about the same as not having one at all. Again, if you can’t reliably draw, aim, and shoot in a couple seconds its better to have bear spray.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The research did find that those using a gun killed the bear roughly 60% of the time, which bear spray will not do.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Here’s some other considerations when carrying a gun:</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>If you miss, are you prepared to shoot the bear who is now on top of you? Do you have a gun that allows appropriate recoil?</li><li>If the bear chooses your hiking partner, are you ready to hit the bear who is on top of them? Meaning, you won’t also shoot your partner.</li><li>Lastly, do you have kids? We’ll discuss this in the next section, but they add a whole new twist. What about using a gun near towns, camping spots, busy trails?</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Guns are great tools for bear defense in adequately trained hands. Use bear spray if not adequately prepared. Use a firearm as a backup to bear spray if you don’t often shoot, which is my strategy. I use bear spray for any surprise situations but also pack a firearm for predatory bears.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you’re comfortable with guns and primarily go on solo or small hunting trips having a weapon as your only defense is a smart choice. If you’re like the rest of us who go on a variety of outings with a variety of people, buy some bear spray.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Kids Using Bear Spray</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Bear spray is excellent for kids in the right situations and training. Bear spray is also dangerous if the child cannot be trusted or not supervised. Don’t leave bear spray in the hands of an idol child or letting them play with bear spray the car. Common sense applies here.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We give our kids bear spray to carry while hiking or when we go on bike rides. The understanding is that it stays in the holder or belt loop unless needed. We also go over how to use it and when. Bear spray is simple to use.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Most kids over the age of 6 can probably use bear spray without issue. All that is needed is remove the cap, point at bear, push on lever. Before our trips we discuss a couple important uses. First, the child can use if bear is at charging them. Second, I ensure the child knows how to use the bear spray if the adults are getting mauled. PLEASE SPRAY ME WITH BEAR SPRAY IF A BEAR IS ON TOP OF ME! This is why bear spray is good for kids. It gives them a tool to save my life.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Proper training applies, but a great resource when needed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-05 07:14:26]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/why-bear-spray-is-important-bear-spray-101-part-1-akrdy/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Essential Gear>Bear Spray]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[Bear Attacks|Bear Spray|Black Bear|Brown Bear|Grizzly Bear|Pepper Spray|Personal Protection|Polar Bear]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Christopher]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Jones]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[2to10@akrdy.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[2to10]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[312]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Bear Spray Specs and Features – Bear Spray 101, Part 2 – AKRDY]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">BLUF:</span></strong></a> Bear spray specs and features are straightforward. Push-button, spray shoots out. There are three areas to check when buying bear spray: the amount of active ingredient, spray distance, spray pattern. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s breakdown all the cool bear spray specs and features for 2020. But like all products don’t get lost in the weeds. Remember, bear spray is about being able to quickly stop a 1500lb bear from eating you so stick to the important features.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Important Bear Spray Features</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Active Ingredient:</span></strong></a> The active ingredient in bear spray is a major consideration. Spoiler, all bear sprays on the market have the same active ingredient, the industry standard for bear spray is Capsaicinoid compounds, with a max concentration of 2.0%. Honestly, every major bear spray uses the same active ingredient and most max out the concentration.</li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Shooting Distance:</span></strong></a> This should make intuitive sense. You want a bear spray that shoots far so that the bear doesn’t end up at your feet. It also gives you more time to get spray into the air as the bear is running towards you. If you spray enough some of it is bound to get on the bear. Bear spray, distance isn’t the only determination here. We also want a spray pattern that fogs, see next.</li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Spray Pattern:</span></strong></a> This isn’t a backyard game of super soakers. The spray pattern from a can of bear spray should fog up not stream. Again, thinking about a bear running towards you should make this clear. You want to cover as much air with capsaicinoids as possible. If the bear spray only shot out as a stream then we’re back to guns and ensuring we aim accurately. We don’t have time for this. A nice fog ensures that the bear spray covers the entire path in front of the bear and the bear will run into the spray. We want a bear spray that will fog up at the further possible distance.</li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Overall Weight:</span></strong></a> This is a minor consideration but important for some trips. Some backpackers will want to reduce weight whenever possible. There really are about two types of bear spray sizes; 7.9oz and 9.5oz. The can needs to hold enough propellant to shoot the spray to an effective distance. The larger can might be more efficient since it allows a bit more spray and cuts back the need to bring two cans. </li><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">How to Carry:</span></strong></a> Most spray cans will come with a holster of sorts. The most popular is a pouch with a belt loop. This may work for a lot of hikers but just ensure that the product you buy has a holder that works for you. Don’t underestimate the importance of this pouch. Bear spray isn’t going to be effective if you can’t get to it. Don’t stuff bear spray inside your pack, keep it external. UDAP has a nice clip on holster called the griz guard that can clip to multiple locations. Some of the sprays will come with chest holsters as well.</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-05 07:19:15]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/bear-spray-specs-and-features-bear-spray-101-part-2-akrdy/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Essential Gear>Bear Spray]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[Bear Attacks|Bear Spray|Black Bear|Brown Bear|Grizzly Bear|Pepper Spray|Personal Protection|Polar Bear]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Christopher]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Jones]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[2to10@akrdy.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[2to10]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[320]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Top 10 Items to Keep in Your Car for Winter Months - AKRDY]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Winters in Alaska can be beautiful and brutal, especially if you aren’t prepared. Road condition can change quickly during a storm and you want to make sure that your car is stocked with all the things you will need to survive an emergency. With the right plan in place, you can safely travel during cold weather and handle any situation that may arise. Here are the top 10 items you want to purchase and keep available in your car.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>1.&nbsp;&nbsp; Collapsible Snow Shovel</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A collapsible model won’t take up too much room in your trunk and will come in handy whether you or a fellow driver find yourselves caught in the snow. You can use the snow shovel to quickly remove inches of snow from the car’s surface and create space around the car so that you can safely get out of any pinch.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>2.&nbsp;&nbsp; Sand or Non-Clumping Cat Litter</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>During the winter, it is all too easy to find yourself spinning your wheel on slick surfaces. Whether you got caught in a sudden snowfall or you have slid off into a snowbank, it can be tough to gain traction. Hitting the accelerator can mean getting stuck further into the snow. Your best bet is to dig out as much snow from around the tires as possible and cover the surface with sand or non-clumping cat litter. Try to get as much as you can close to and under the tire. This will help create traction so that the tire can catch and go to work getting your car back on the road.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>3.&nbsp;&nbsp; Cold Weather Clothing</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Maybe you are just heading up to the road to the store, so you just grabbed the nearest jacket and didn’t bother with all the accessories. If something goes wrong, this can leave you exposed to dangerously cold conditions. Be sure to always have a blanket, hand warmers, gloves, warm socks and a hat in your vehicle. If you are planning on a long trip, it is also a good idea to pack a sleeping bag.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>4.&nbsp;&nbsp; Road Flares</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If something happens, you want to be able to attract attention and seek out help as soon as possible. Road flares can be used to help illuminate your car and signal your location to other drivers and emergency personnel. Be sure to purchase road flares with the longest burning time available and have several available so that you can ignite a few rounds of flares if needed.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>5.&nbsp;&nbsp; Flashlight</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In some locations in Alaska, the winter means weeks without seeing the sun. At the very least, you will be dealing with shorter days and long nights, so be sure to include a durable and waterproof flashlight in your safety kit. Keep an extra set of batteries nearby or opt for a hand crank version so that you never have to worry about running out of power.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>6.&nbsp;&nbsp; Bottled Water and Food</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When you are surrounded by snow, it doesn’t seem like you would have to worry about a ready supply of water. However, consuming snow to stay hydrated during an emergency can be a dangerous choice. If your body is already struggling to stay warm, eating snow can drop your internal temperature. Bottled water will help you stay warm and hydrated. Some high calories snacks can also help if you are stranded for a long period of time.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>7.&nbsp;&nbsp; First Aid Kit</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>No matter what the weather, you should always have a first aid kit in your car. Be sure to purchase a kit that includes: band-aides, antibacterial ointment, antiseptic wipes, medical wrap and adhesive tape. These items will allow you to handle a wide range of medical emergencies and dress any cuts or scrapes until you can get to a professional.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>8.&nbsp;&nbsp; Multi-Purpose Tool</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It is a good idea to invest in a multi-purpose tool and keep it handy in your car. Instead of storing a pocket knife, screwdrivers, scissors, wrenches and other tools, you can have a compact solution that can help with practically any situation. There are models that include over twenty different tools including saw blades and hammers. You can choose a combination of tools that best fits your needs and be prepared for emergencies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>9.&nbsp;&nbsp; Cell Phone Charger</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Many of us are guilty of letting our phone’s battery drain. In normal circumstances, this can be an annoying inconvenience, but in an emergency, it can be a real problem. Avoid getting caught with a dead phone by keeping an extra charger in your car. You may even want to go one step further and include a charging pack so that you don’t have to rely on the car’s battery as a source of power.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>10. Jumper Cables</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Cold weather is hard on your car’s battery. When the temperature drops to 32℉, your battery loses 35% of its power. At 0℉, your battery is operating at just 40% of its normal strength and your engine will need twice as much current to start the engine. That is why it isn’t uncommon to need a boost during the winter months. Avoid getting stuck in the cold by having a set of jumper cables in your trunk.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you have to jump your car, remember that the positive cable connects to the positive terminal. Both the positive and negative terminal should be clearly marked, but if you are having trouble reading the label, the positive terminal is usually slightly bigger. In addition, the positive jumper cable will be red and the negative cable will be black. Keep these details in mind so that you aren’t left guessing during a stressful situation.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>+1: Tow Strap</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Last but not least, have a tow strap handy. Find a strap that is rated for the weight of your car. If you're not sure, use 5000lb for most small cars and 10,000lbs for SUVs and Trucks. It's also important that you actually attach it to your tow brackets to ensure it works. Some tow brackets require clips to attach.  A tow strap will be helpful for your car and if needed you just might have the tools to help someone else out. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While you can’t prevent accidents, you can do your best to be prepared for the unexpected. Keeping these 10 items in your car will help you survive the winter months and handle a variety of emergency situations. Start putting together your winter car kit now so that you are ready when the weather turns cold.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-07 20:51:31]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/top-10-items-to-keep-in-your-car-for-winter-months/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Owning a Car in Alaska]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[Personal Protection|Traveling Alaska|Winter travel]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[322]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Top 10 Items to Always Have When Hiking - AKRDY]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whether you are heading out for an easy hike at your local park or you are about to tackle an expert level trail that will have you hiking for most of the day, preparation is key. You want to make sure you have all the Top 10 hiking essentials you need to handle changing weather conditions, respond to an emergency, and survive to be outdoors for extended periods of time. This doesn’t mean that you will have to lug around pounds of bulky equipment. With the right tools and clothing, you can safely enjoy any hike and be prepared for the unexpected. To help you plan for your next hike, here are the 10 items you will always want to have with you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>1.&nbsp;&nbsp; The Right Footwear</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Investing in the right hiking boots can make all the difference in the world. It won’t take long for ill-fitting shoes to start causing blisters and if you get caught in the rain or have to deal with wet trails, you can end up soaked and cold. When looking for the right hiking boot, you will want to take into account fit, water resistance, durability, weight, and warmth.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you plan on tackling more difficult terrain, you may want the extra protection and support of above ankle boots. However, in most cases, ankle-high boots should do the job. In addition, if you will be dealing with cold temperatures, be sure to get a boot that provides adequate warmth. For warmer hikes, focus on breathable liners and materials that allow for airflow that increases comfort.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Above, all, you want a well-fitting boot. That means a tight heel and a little bit of wiggle room in the toes. This will provide additional room for thick socks and allow for some movement.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>2.&nbsp;&nbsp; A Map and Compass</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It is important to bring navigational tools and knowledge to use them. While most people rely on their phones and GPS devices, there is always the chance that technology will fail. You might find yourself out of range of a signal or your battery can die. When that happens, a compass and map will be enough for you to orient yourself and find your way back.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>3.&nbsp;&nbsp; Rain Gear and Extra Clothes</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>No matter how many times you checked the weather, conditions can change quickly and you can find yourself in the middle of windy, cold, and/or wet weather. Raingear is essential for every trip. Be sure to bring rain gear and extra clothes that take into account the season and how long you expect to be outside. Focus on layering and packing quick-drying items. Also, always include socks, gloves and a warm hat. These clothing items can help protect your extremities and regulate your overall body temperature.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>4.&nbsp;&nbsp; A Fire Starter</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Many people make sure that they have a butane lighter on them, but you will want to go the extra mile and bring along waterproof matches or matches stored in a waterproof container. An even better strategy is to purchase a flint or magnesium firestarter. These products come with a striker that can be hit against a bar of flint in order to produce sparks. Bring along a baggie of dryer lint and you will have the perfect ignitable material and a firestarter that will operate in any conditions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>5.&nbsp;&nbsp; Headlamp</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you find yourself still out on the trail once it gets dark, a headlamp can be an invaluable safety tool. The hands-free design will allow you to keep your balance or manage other items and the power light will illuminate the trail so that you don’t trip over logs, rock, and other hazards in your way. The light can also help you avoid any unwanted wildlife encounters.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>6.&nbsp;&nbsp; First Aid Kit</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It should go without saying that a first aid kit should always be a part of any hiking outing. You never know when an injury or illness will occur and even the simplest of medical supplies can make a big difference.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>7.&nbsp;&nbsp; Multi-Tool that Includes a Knife</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Number 7 of the Top 10 hiking essentials is a solid multi-tool. While a good knife can get you out of any number of sticky situations, a multi-tool is even more versatile. Look for a product that comes with a knife, small saw blade and pliers. Some models even include a small ax head and silverware. Whether you go for a simpler or more complex model, a multi-tool can help with repairing gear, creating a shelter, and administering first aid.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>8.&nbsp;&nbsp; Sun Protection</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Even during the winter months, exposure to too much sun can be dangerous and snow blindness can occur as the rays reflect off the surface of the snow. Throughout the year, you will want to have sunscreen, sunglasses and protective clothing to limit UV rays. Look for a sunscreen with an SPF 30, which can block 97% of UVB rays.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>9.&nbsp;&nbsp; Temporary Shelter</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A temporary shelter can be a lightweight space blanket or ultralight tarp. You want something that is going to keep you warm, safe, and protected from the elements. While a tent is great, you probably don’t want to be carrying around that much weight. Any emergency shelter should be lightweight and portable enough that you always have it on you in case you become injured or stranded.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>10.&nbsp; Plenty of Water and Purifying Tools</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a general rule, most people need a half-liter of water per hour. Be sure to bring enough supplies based on how long you expect to hike. If the temperatures are high and it is going to be a strenuous hike, you will want to bring extra water. To help survive during emergencies, pack your choice of water purifying tools. Iodine tablets are an inexpensive, effective, and lightweight option, but you will have to wait 20-30 minutes for the water to be purified. For faster results, you can use a water filter, but this approach requires manual pumping and the unit will add weight to your pack.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>These Top 10 hiking essentials will help you safely enjoy a hike and handle practically any situation. As you shop around for the best products for your hiking pack, remember to focus on lightweight items that can serve multiple purposes. There are plenty of versatile products on the market that will help you safely enjoy the outdoors.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-07 20:55:34]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/10-items-to-always-have-when-hiking/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Hiking]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[Hiking|Personal Protection]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[328]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Snagging Hook Central - Alaska Fishing 101, Part 5]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Bottom Line Up Front (BLUF):</strong> Snagging is a great way to fill the freezer. Find a cheap source for snagging hooks, you’ll likely lose a few while fishing. Most hooks will be of similar quality.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska offers a very unique fishing opportunity in snagging fish. You don’t have to be a resident to snag fish, just need a fishing license. Snagging fish is only allowed in specific saltwater locations. Generally, this is saltwater near Seward and Prince William Sound. Check the Alaska Fish and Game website for current regulations.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yes, snagging fish means taking a large treble hook and casting into the water and pulling the hook quickly through the water until you snag into a fish. The hook can snag any part of the fish. It doesn’t have to be the mouth. Snagging isn’t like using lures, the fish won’t bite the snagging hook. Snagging fish is a method of harvesting fish. Although there is some sport to the process, mostly this is about filling your freezer with fish. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This doesn’t make snagging fish bad, its just a unique way of fishing that is not found in many other places. Snagging fish is a great way to fill the freezer, much like dip netting. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Types of Snagging Hooks</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The most common style of snagging hooks is a weighted style with the weight attached to the main shank of the hook. All snagging hooks have a treble, three, hooks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Columbia River Tackle makes a weighted treble hook with the weight the extends out of the back of the hook. The theory for this style is that it opens up the hooks for more room to snag the fish. The weight for these hooks is usually the same amount just located behind the hook.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some of the other manufactures make hooks with the weight in various shapes. We’re not aware of any advantage this offers in snagging fish.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Common Snagging Hook Sizes</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>10/0 (pronounced ten ought), 8/0, or 6/0 are the most common sizes for snagging hooks. Most fishers use 10/0 or 8/0. You can find snagging hooks as small as 4/0 at places like Walmart or Fred Meyer and as large as 14/0. The practicality of using hooks that are too small or too large may outweigh the perceived benefit.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Generally speaking, hooks of smaller size will have less weight and will be cheaper. Conversely, bigger hooks will be more costly and have a larger weight. The advantage of having more, or less, the weight will come into play when you target specific fish. Also in different waters having a smaller hook may be more advantageous to prevent snagging on non-fish objects.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">What is the recommended size of snagging hooks for catching salmon in Alaska?</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The recommended size for snagging salmon in Alaska is 10/0. These sizes is commonly found in stores, cheap, and big enough to do the job right. They do cost more money but have the weight to sink fast. They work well in large bodies of water like Seward or Prince William Sound.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some anglers will prefer 8/0 because they are cheaper and less heavy. This decrease in weight can help delay arm fatigue and may allow kids to participate. Like everything in life each angler will develop their own preference so try a few sizes out and see what works for you. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Snagging Hook Manufactures</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There’s not many large snagging hook manufactures. In our research here’s a list that we found smallest to largest, or local to international:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><strong>Columbia River Tackle (CRT):</strong> CRT is located in Chugiak, AK. A small company that mostly operates from the garage. They make lots of lures and weights, to include both styles of snagging hooks. This includes the custom style and weight behind style.</li><li><strong>Matzuo America:</strong> Matzuo is a part of Big Game America. They are a big company with years of experience making hooks and lures. They offer the classic snagging hook variety.</li><li><strong>Danielson:</strong> Danielson is also another big name brand company that makes many styles of lures and fishing equipment. They make classic weighted snagging hooks.</li><li><strong>Home Made:</strong> Weighted snagging treble hooks are easy to make and you can find them for sale on Facebook or local sales channels.</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Places to Buy Snagging Hooks</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><strong>Akrdy.com:</strong> Ok, so we’re biased, but check out our online store. We usually will have the cheapest prices and free shipping to JBER. We also carry a wide assortment of sizes and styles.</li><li><strong>B&amp;J Sporting Goods:</strong> This is a local store, located off Northern Lights Blvd in mid-town Anchorage. Great expertise and knowledge of gear, location, and species to target.</li><li><strong>Fred Meyer / Walmart:</strong> I lump these together because they are technically local but they offer a random assortment of hooks at times. For example, you can get some really cheap hooks from Fred Meyer but you need to buy a 10 pack and they only come in sizes 4/0, 5/0, and 6/0. The 6/0 size was sold out at the time of this writing. I’ve heard Walmart is a great place to buy as well.</li><li><strong>Amazon:</strong> As usual, you can find the standard hook sizes from Matzuo and Danielson on Amazon.</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">How to Snag Fish In Alaska</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Fish snagging hooks like other lures. The speed at which they are dragged through the water and the depth of the hook will determine how many fish you catch. In addition, time should be taken to determine where the fish are located in the water to ensure the hook is at the correct depth.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The primary species of fish that anglers target is Sockeye Salmon, commonly called red salmon or ‘reds’. Generally speaking, Red Salmon will be near the top of the water and edges. This will be the same for Coho, aka Silver, salmon. For example, if fishing at McDonalds machine works in Seward, these are smaller streams, and depth without the tide is only a couple of feet. In these conditions, look to target the salmon a couple of feet from the bank. In order to do this, you’ll need to keep the hook lower in the water so that it is in the strike zone near the shore.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For areas of deeper water like the Seward lagoon outflow. You will want to target about 20 feet off shore. In some cases, you can see the schools of fish swimming in front of you. This is deeper water but the salmon will still stay close to the surface. Keeping your retrieval fast will ensure you’re up in the zone.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Snagging Strategies</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The speed of retrieval will determine the depth the hook sinks. Slower retrieval will lead to an increased depth. Regardless of how fast you’re able to reel, your hook will have a sinking motion followed by a quick upturn when the rod is whipped back. Pull the rod off to your side to ensure the hook is kept at the optimum depth. This will make the hook travel along a more flat line.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What you want to avoid is the hook being too close to the surface or too far on the bottom. If on the surface the hook will likely come out of the water, turning into missile vs snagging fish. If the hook is too far on the bottom, it will have a higher chance of snagging of debris.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You can prevent either by allowing the hook to fall to the bottom just after you cast, and pausing during retrieval to allow the hook to sink further into the water.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Problems with Snagging</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The most obvious is the danger with snagging is the hook itself. Anytime you are casting, retrieving, and pulling a 1-3 oz weighted treble hook through the water you will have problems. These problems are compounded when hundreds of like-minded people are swinging their snagging hooks around as well. For this reason, give anyone snagging a bit more room then you would another angler.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Flying Hooks</span></strong></a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The other issue is when the hook comes out of the water. Most times when the hook leaves the water force of pulling it through the water transforms the hook to a missile. If you’re pulling overhead the hook will shoot straight to you. Pulling from the side helps your cause but you need to watch for people around you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you hit someone with the treble hook it may not hook the person. It may just give them a good blow to the head or chest. This is not a good strategy to make friends fishing. Needless to say, prevention is best. Watch your own hook but also keep a lookout for other chuckleheads who may hit you with theirs. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The other issue is in the off chance your knot break and the weighted treble hook goes flying. The nature of casting causes a whipping action at the end of your line. This whipping effect stresses the knots you tie. After a couple of hours, if you don’t have good knots, you won’t have a hook. Not a huge deal but this can be dangerous for others.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To prevent injury, tie good knots, wear eye protection, and stay away from others.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Snagging on other items then fish</span></strong></a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The other problem with snagging is that you’re prone to lose hooks. These hooks are large and sharp. They will hook into anything from rocks, wood, another lost fishing line, or simply piles of algae. Some of this you can pull in and remove from the hook, other items won’t give your hooks back.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Prevent this by simply learning where to cast. If you know where the snags are you need to avoid them. The Seward lagoon outflow is notorious for having lots of snags, especially near the outflow. At high tide is nearly impossible to see any of the snags. At low tide, you can see where they are. When fishing Seward lagoon outflow for the first time start at low tide and work the tide up. I promise, snagging is much more fun when you don’t lose hooks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second way to deal with snags is having a setup that allows for easier time breaking off your leader. Use a smaller weight leader attached to your mainline, i.e. 20lb test. This way if you get snagged it’ll break off faster and you can retie and move on quicker.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Knots in your line</span></strong></a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The downfall of a faster retrieval is that your main line is more likely to get caught on the tip of your rod. This occurs when after you pull the rod back if you don’t reel as fast as you move the rod forward. Any extra line will get wrapped around the rod tip. This is not a big deal, just annoying. It takes time to unwrap the line. Your rod type will make this worse, in addition to how fast you’re reeling the hook. Medium and light action rod tips will bounce around a lot more making it more likely you’ll tie up your line on the tip.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To prevent the line from getting wrapped try a heavier action rod with less tip flex. Also, pause after you pull back on the rod to reel in the extra slack. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color"><strong>Shoulder Injuries While Snagging Fish</strong></span></a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Pulling the hook through the water is taxing on the body. Snagging is not an easy fishing tactic. It requires either the repeated twisting at the waist or pulling from the arms and shoulders. For this reason, its not uncommon to have sore shoulders. Using your waist to pull the hook can take the stress off your shoulders and vice versa. To do this, hold the rod close to the chest and use your waist movement to do the majority of the work. This is important when the fish aren’t running very strong. In those cases, you might go hours without catching fish and for most people, this just adds insult to injury.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><a><span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color">Kids and Snagging Fish</span></a></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bringing kids to snag fish should take some careful thought. It really depends on the age, maturity, and your desire to snag. Provide direct supervision to kids younger than five. Direct supervision is by someone who is not fishing. This is due to the number of snag hooks flying around. The child's maturity should determine where to bring older children. If the child is prone to wandering aimlessly, like most children of that age range, then it might be best to stay at camp. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Older kids can snag but given the hard work required wouldn’t expect much from them until they are at least 10, if not 12. Just keep an eye on them to ensure others anglers don’t cut in on them. Some adults will try to take advantage of the kid's fishing spot. Fishing should be enjoyable for everyone, including kids. Given the inexperience of kids, they’ll need more room and time to learn. Allow them the space to learn and they will help fill the bag limits. More importantly, everyone will have fun.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-07 23:18:21]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/snagging-hook-central-alaska-fishing-101-part-5/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Fishing]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[4th of July Beach Seward|Chinook Salmon|Coghill Lake|Coho Salmon|King Salmon|Lagoon Outflow Seward|Lowell Beach Seward|Main Bay Prince William Sound|McDonalds Machine Works|Nash Road|Red Salmon|Seward|Seward Culvert|Seward Waterfall|Shakespeare Creek|Silver Salmon|Snag Hooks|Sockeye Salmon|Sunny Cove]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Christopher]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Jones]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[2to10@akrdy.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[2to10]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[333]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[The Great Alaskan Earthquake of 1964]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The <a href="https://www.history.com/topics/natural-disasters-and-environment/1964-alaska-earthquake#section_4">Alaskan earthquake of 1964</a> is the largest recorded in the United States. This event not only resulted in extensive damage and loss of life, it also reshaped the local landscape, changed the field of earth science and introduced new construction practices.The earthquake marks a major point in Alaskan history and continues to provide valuable lessons for both residents and scientists.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>History of the 1964 Earthquake</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On March 27, 1964, which also happened to be Good Friday, a magnitude 9.2 earthquake shook Alaska at 5:35 local time. It lasted a full 4.5 minutes. While the epicenter was located in Prince William sound, just 74 miles southeast of Anchorage, the earthquake was powerful enough to register in 47 out of 50 states. In fact, the earthquake was so massive that Seattle’s icon Space Needle, a full 1,200 miles away, was noticeably swaying. There are only two other earthquakes that have registered with a higher magnitude: the 1960 9.5 magnitude quake in Chile and the 9.3 magnitude quake that shook the Indian Ocean off the coast of Sumatra.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Unfortunately, the initial earthquake was only the beginning. The seismic activity triggered tsunamis and landslides and destroyed entire communities. Residents lost power, telephone lines and were stranded when roads collapsed and railroads were ruined. While the death toll was reported at 131, only 15 of those deaths are attributed to the first tremors. Most people perished during subsequent events.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Landslides and Tsunamis</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":335,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wave-11061_640.jpg" alt="Tsunami Wave" class="wp-image-335"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Since the earthquake struck right at the coast, it didn’t take long for the tsunamis to bring massive waves crashing onto the shore. Just four minutes after the main quake ceased, a tidal wave wiped out a third of the population in the tiny town of Chenga. Kodiak, Seward and Whittier also experienced significant damage due to tsunamis that caused a <a href="https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/news/great-alaska-earthquake#:~:text=On%20the%20morning%20of%20March,and%20took%20over%20139%20lives.">rise in sea levels of up to 170 feet</a> in certain areas.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The earthquake also caused landslides across the state. In some places, the soil actually began behaving like liquid, which caused a district of Anchorage to drop a full nine feet and carried an entire bluff in Turnagain Heights out into the ocean. With so little time between major events, most residents didn’t have the opportunity to find safety, In the weeks following the earthquake aftershocks continued on a regular basis, some of which registered up to a 6.2 magnitude.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>How Did the Earthquake Reshape Alaska?</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Residents who experienced the earthquake describe seeing the earth move in waves, which caused permanent changes to the landscape. For example, some areas near Kodiak were raised by 30 feet. Meanwhile, in Turnagain Arm and surrounding areas, the land dropped 8 feet. In the oil port of Valdez, which sat on a foundation of compacted sand and gravel, the soil turned to liquid, which sent much of the city into the port. At the same time, a tsunami hit the area and oil tanks caught on fire, basically decimating the entire city. Today, the rebuilt city of Valdez sits 6 miles away from its original location.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>What Caused the 1964 Earthquake?</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In 1964, scientists didn’t have a clear understanding of what caused earthquakes. The theory of tectonic plates was controversial and not widely accepted. Since then, scientists have identified 12 main tectonic plates that make up the lithosphere, or the outer layer of the earth’s surface. These plates are constantly moving. The fastest plate moves about <a href="https://www.sciencenewsforstudents.org/article/quake-shook-geology-alaska-1964">6 inches every year while the slowest plates move just under 2.5 centimeters annually</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Where these plates converge, there can be collisions that trigger major events on the earth’s surface. Alaska happens to sit on fault formed by the Pacific and North American Plates. The Pacific Plate happens to be denser, which causes it to slide underneath the North American Plate. The movement of these two plates is responsible for creating over <a href="https://www.tripsavvy.com/earthquakes-in-alaska-1454750#:~:text=Alaska%20has%2011%25%20of%20the,and%2010%2C000%20quakes%20overall%20annually.">10,000 quakes</a> every year.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While the earthquake was a devastating event that happened without warning, it led to significant advances in Geology and our understanding of the earth. USGS geologist, <a href="https://www.adn.com/alaska-news/article/seismic-shift-how-1964-alaska-earthquake-changed-science/2014/03/24/">George Plafker</a>, played a major role in studying the 1964 earthquake and proving the existence of tectonic plates, which is now widely accepted as fact. He was also able to show that plates didn’t just move vertically, but also horizontally.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Plafker began by paying close attention to the areas of Alaska that experienced the most significant rise and fall of land. He located a previously unknown fault and concluded that centuries of compression between the Pacific and North American plates had built up pressure that simply could no longer be stopped by the friction of the plates. This energy was released in the form of an earthquake.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>How the Earthquake Changed Construction Practices</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":337,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/excavators-1174428_640.jpg" alt="Earthquake construction practices" class="wp-image-337"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In response to the destruction of the 1964 earthquake, Alaska changed many of its building practices. Today, buildings are required to adhere to standards set forth by the International Building Code. All structural elements must be reinforced and capable with withstanding motion. Walls are constructed with reinforced concrete and roofs are kept as light as possible. All plumbing and electrical components are installed in a way that allows for movement. Roads and bridges are also built according to the highest standards, which has allowed the state to weather frequent earthquakes with minimal damage and loss of life.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Part of living in Alaska and enjoying all the natural wonders and wilderness also means dealing with regular earthquakes. There is no way to predict exactly when the next mega quake will hit, which is why preparedness is essential. While the 1964 earthquake was devastating, it also led to important discoveries about tectonic plates and earth science and helped to create new standards for construction that are still helping to protect residents.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-24 05:01:25]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/the-great-alaskan-earthquake-of-1964/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/denali-national-park-1733313_640.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wave-11061_640.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/excavators-1174428_640.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[denali-national-park-1733313_640.jpg|wave-11061_640.jpg|excavators-1174428_640.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/denali-national-park-1733313_640.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wave-11061_640.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/excavators-1174428_640.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[334|335|337]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[denali-national-park-1733313_640|wave-11061_640|excavators-1174428_640]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[1964 Alaska Earthquake Denali National Park||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/denali-national-park-1733313_640.jpg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[339]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[The 2018 Alaskan Earthquake]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While most people associate earthquakes with California, Alaska is also an earthquake prone state and the site of the 1964 megathrust earthquake that registered a magnitude of 9.2, which is the second largest quake on record. In the decades after this historic earthquake, Alaska continued to experience around tens of thousands quakes per year, but none of them came close to the power and magnitude of the 1964 event until November 30, 2018.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At 8:23 in the morning, the earthquake struck Alaska. Point Mackenzie, which is 10 miles north of Anchorage, was identified as the epicenter. It registered as a 7.1 magnitude earthquake that occurred 19 miles beneath the earth’s surface. After the initial quake, over 80 aftershocks shook the region throughout the days, some of which measured over 5.0 magnitude. Tsunami warnings were issued immediately, but ultimately, no tsunamis were triggered. The aftershocks continued for months after the earthquake although they continued to weaken in intensity.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Cause of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Anchorage_earthquake#:~:text=On%20November%2030%2C%202018%2C%20at,earthquake%20hit%20South%20Central%20Alaska.&amp;text=It%20was%20followed%20six%20minutes,north%2Dnorthwest%20of%20the%20municipality.">2018 Alaskan Earthquake</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":342,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-907724_1920-1024x681.jpg" alt="2018 Alaskan earthquake - mountain scenery" class="wp-image-342"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Following the massive quake of 1964, which resulted in 139 deaths and extensive damage, scientists made major strides in understanding what causes earthquakes. The 1964 megathrust caused large areas of land to rise in some locations and fall in others. By studying these locations, scientists were able to confirm the existence of tectonic plates. Up to that point, the plates were merely part of a theory that the scientific community had yet to accept as fact.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska happens to sit on the boundary of two of the major plates that make up the lithosphere, or the upper layer of the earth’s crust. The smaller Pacific plate is moving in a northwest direction at a pace of 2.8 inches per year and colliding with the massive North American plate. Since the Pacific plate isn’t big enough to actually move the larger plate, it is actually moving under the North American plate in a process known as subduction.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Subduction boundaries are responsible for the most powerful earthquakes. Other plates interact in ways that may still cause earthquakes, but they are much less severe. For example, a transform fault occurs when plates move horizontally against each other in a strike-slip motion. In these instances, there is some space for movement. Subduction is a much more violent action that produces record breaking earthquakes.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Damage Caused by the Earthquake</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":344,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/asphalt-315756_1280-1024x768.jpg" alt="damaged road" class="wp-image-344"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While 117 people were injured during the quake, there were no fatalities and relatively little damage considering the power of the earthquake. Some homes and businesses experienced damage, but there were no major building or bridge collapses. Beside a few roads where the asphalt cracked and collapsed, the infrastructure remained intact. This was excellent news for emergency crews who were bracing for the worst and preparing to deal with rescue efforts in freezing temperatures and limited daylight.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Local residents had several things working in their favor when the earthquake hit. The depth of the earthquake (29 feet) meant that the shocks didn’t travel very far. If the quake would have occurred closer to the surface, communities would likely have faced more challenges. The time of the quake was also serendipitous. At 8:23, first responders were in the middle of a shift change, which meant that there were more police and firefighters on hand and ready to respond to calls for help.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>After the 1964 earthquake, experts agreed that it was just a matter of time before another megathrust hit the area. Officials in Anchorage immediately took action and began implementing <a href="https://www.curbed.com/2018/12/3/18124154/alaska-earthquake-anchorage-building-codes">new building codes</a>, moving cities further away from the coast and enacting other emergency readiness protocols. The buildings that were able to withstand the 2018 earthquake were built according to Anchorage construction standards. Areas that suffered the heaviest damage were not required to follow the same building plan reviews and inspections.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Lessons from the 2018 Alaskan Earthquake</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The damage from the quake clearly showed that the municipal building codes work and protect people and buildings. That is why experts are pushing for the Alaska Legislature to pass laws that require public buildings to be built according to seismic codes. Businesses who need to update their buildings may be eligible for subsidies to help fund renovations.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The earthquake also revealed some problems with communication in cities outside Anchorage. In Mat-Su, there was a <a href="https://www.adn.com/alaska-news/anchorage/2019/11/28/last-years-71-earthquake-woke-alaska-up-experts-say-it-wasnt-a-true-test-of-our-readiness/">complete breakdown of communication </a>and no information was posted until 90 minutes after the quake. It also took three days for local officials to hold a press conference with updates and information. This was an obvious failure in leadership.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition, it was discovered that most of the damage to buildings was caused by sprinkler systems that broke and caused flooding. As a result, firefighters are recommending that buildings install additional bracing and flexible water lines for sprinklers. This will allow for more freedom of movement and hopefully prevent water damage.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It is clear that implementing new building codes after the 1964 earthquake has been helpful. However, there are still areas for improvement. While Anchorage was able to weather the 2018 Alaskan earthquake quake relatively well, it wasn’t the “big one” and that is what the state needs to be prepared to handle. The assumption is that tsunamis wouldn’t be able to reach Anchorage, but scientists are pushing for more research into this area in order to avoid catastrophe.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ultimately, earthquakes are a part of living in Alaska and there is no way to predict when the next one will hit. That is why preparation is key. Both individual residents and communities need to take steps to prepare for earthquakes, including the next megathrust, which could set a new record for magnitude.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-24 05:02:03]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/the-2018-alaskan-earthquake/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-907724_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/asphalt-315756_1280.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[alaska-907724_1920.jpg|asphalt-315756_1280.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/alaska-907724_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/asphalt-315756_1280.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[342|344]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[alaska-907724_1920|asphalt-315756_1280]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[|]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[|]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[|]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[349]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[How to Prepare for an Earthquake]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While people commonly associate earthquakes with California, Alaska also experiences frequent and powerful earthquakes. In fact, there are about <a href="https://seismic.alaska.gov/earthquake-risk.html#:~:text=Forty%20five%20magnitude%205%20to,located%20in%20Alaska%20each%20month">1,000 earthquakes per month</a> and about 45 exceed a magnitude 5 each year. Alaska has also been the site of the second strongest earthquake in history, which took place in 1964 was recorded at 9.2 magnitude. The state sits at the intersection of two major tectonic plates, which means that these earthquakes will continue to happen and it is inevitable that another megathrust earthquake will hit the region at some point. Since there is nothing we can do to predict or prevent earthquakes, preparation is key. Follow these tips to prepare for an earthquake.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>How to Protect Your Home</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":353,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/construction-370588_1920-1024x683.jpg" alt="new home construction for earthquake proof buildings" class="wp-image-353"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Over the years, we have learned a lot about how to construct buildings and homes that are more resistant to earthquakes. If you are building a new home, be sure to work with a contractor who is well-versed in seismic codes and can help incorporate the latest tools and techniques into your home. For older homes, there are retrofitting options that can help to sure up the structural components of your home so that it is better able to withstand strong tremors. While this can require some investment, it can be worth the money in order to improve safety, especially if you live in Alaska.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Protecting Non-Structural Items</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are also some easy to implement best practices that will help to protect non-structural items in your home.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>Be sure to securely fasten bookshelves and cabinets to the wall. Use metal brackets that can be screwed into the wall studs to help hold everything in place.<br></li><li>When it comes to storage, be careful about placing heavy items on lower shelves so that they don’t come tumbling down or topple the shelving.<br></li><li>Reinforced ceiling fans and any hanging light fixtures.</li><li>Bolt heavy appliances, such as refrigerators and water headers to the floor. </li><li>Avoid hanging pictures or mirrors over beds or seating areas.</li><li>Be diligent about repairing any cracks so that they don’t expand with the vibrations from the earthquake.</li><li>Store any flammable liquids or chemicals on the bottom shelf of locked cabinets. </li><li>Replace any rigid wiring and piping with more flexible options that will allow them to move without breaking during an earthquake.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Prepare Your Family for an Earthquake</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It is important to establish a plan of action and make sure that every member of the family knows where to go and what to do in the event of an earthquake or other emergency. There should be safe places within the home that can offer additional protection during an earthquake. Discuss these often so that everyone automatically seeks shelter in these areas without panicking.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You should also identify a safe meeting place where everyone can gather once it is safe to move. This will help keep track of everyone and prevent family members from being separated during an emergency. The meeting location should be easily accessible and consider making it on higher ground in case the earthquake triggers tsunamis.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When an earthquake hits, you should drop, cover and hold on. If there is a desk or table nearby, take cover under this item and stay put until the tremors stop. In situations where you aren’t near any obvious cover, crouch down next to an interior wall.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Create an Emergency Kit</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":351,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/first-aid-kit-62643_1920-1024x768.jpg" alt="make a first aid kit" class="wp-image-351"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a general rule, you want to have two weeks of supplies, including food, water and medicine on hand and ready to go in the case of an emergency. In addition to these items, make sure your kit has:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>A hand crank or battery powered radio. This may be essential to receiving news and information</li><li>Flashlights and extra batteries</li><li>Dust masks to help protect your and your family from contaminated air from dirt and debris</li><li>A manual can opener so that you can easily access food</li><li>A multitool that includes a wrench or pliers in case you need to turn off utility supply lines</li><li>Plastic sheeting or a small tent in case you need to shelter in place&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>First aid kit</li><li>A sleeping bag for each person in the family</li><li>Fire extinguisher</li><li>Change of clothes, including a pair of sturdy shoes</li><li>A cell phone battery charger</li><li>Books, games or puzzles. If you end up stranded for a few days, you will be glad to have a little entertainment.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You should store your emergency kit in plastic bins or duffel bags that can keep the items cool and dry during storage. Also make sure that the kit is easily accessible and not packed away at the back of the garage. Based on your climate and your family, you may want to add other items to the kit, but this list should give you a good start with till help you survive until emergency crews can offer additional help.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the years following the megathrust earthquake of 1964, Anchorage and surrounding communities made major changes to building codes and began preparing public spaces for future earthquakes. Over the ensuing decades the city and the state have been able to successfully weather thousands of quakes with minimal damage and injuries. However, these successes should not make people complacent when it comes to earthquake preparedness. More powerful earthquakes are on the horizon and it is vital that residents take steps to prepare their homes and create an emergency plan that can easily be put into action when the next big quake hits.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-06-24 05:01:05]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/how-to-prepare-for-an-earthquake/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mountains-1622731_1280.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/first-aid-kit-62643_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/construction-370588_1920.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[mountains-1622731_1280.jpg|first-aid-kit-62643_1920.jpg|construction-370588_1920.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mountains-1622731_1280.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/first-aid-kit-62643_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/construction-370588_1920.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[350|351|353]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[mountains-1622731_1280|first-aid-kit-62643_1920|construction-370588_1920]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[Alaskan mountains||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mountains-1622731_1280.jpg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[366]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[How to Prevent Moose Attacks]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://akrdy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Living in Alaska</a> means that you are bound to have some wildlife encounters. With 200,000 Alaskan Moose throughout the state, there is a good chance that you will get close to one of these enormous animals. On average, an adult moose will stand over six feet at the shoulder and weigh well over a 1,000 pounds. While they aren’t usually aggressive, they will attack if they feel threatened and their sheer size makes them a potential danger to humans. That is why it is important to know what to do to prevent a moose attack.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Moose Behavior</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For most of the year, the Alaskan moose is a solitary creature. If you encounter more than one, it may be mating season, which is when these animals can turn aggressive. Mating or rutting season tends to peak in lake September and early October. During this period, males may work together to herd females and create a sort of moose harem. While the cows tend to lay in pits, the males will fight for the right to mate. In fact, a moose’s neck will double in size during the rut so that they can more effectively spare with other males. A female will typically only mate with one male, so mature bulls have to ward off younger bulls and in some cases, the fight can result in death.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>During the summer months, moose spend most of their time leisurely looking for food and tend to be slow-moving. They are not territorial animals, so if you come across one in the wild, you should be able to safely observe it from a distance and slowly exit the situation. When startled moose are known to attack humans throughout the year. In addition, mothers can be protective over their calves, so beware if you see a young moose. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Natural Moose Predators</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":370,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wolves-4377376_1920-1024x724.jpg" alt="wolf pack hunting" class="wp-image-370"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While moose are enormous animals, they are hunted by natural predators in the wild. <mark>A pack of gray wolves can effectively overtake and kill a moose, and brown bears are also known to attack, although these animals will typically look for smaller calves and avoid large bulls.</mark> </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Historically, humans have been the deadliest predator for moose although Alaska has established <a href="http://www.adfg.alaska.gov/index.cfm?adfg=moosehunting.unit20e#:~:text=Season%3A%20September%208%E2%80%9317,No%20quota" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">clear restrictions</a> when it comes to hunting these creatures in order to preserve their numbers. For non-residents, the hunting season lasts from September 8-17 and requires a permit. Hunters are only allowed to kill one moose and their antlers have to be at least 50 inches or have over 4 brow tines. Alaskan residents have an extra hunting window from August 24-28 although they are still limited to one mature bull.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>What to Do if You Encounter a Moose</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are some basic rules of wildlife etiquette that will help keep both you and moose safe:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>Never feed wildlife. Moose have a very specialized diet that is nutrient-rich and low in fiber. Not only is feeding a moose danger for humans, but the design of the digestive system of a moose can not handle something as simple as hay. It can actually kill a moose. In addition, feeding a moose comes with a $110 fine. </li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true,"start":2} -->
<ol start="2"><li>Keep your distance. If you notice that the moose’s behavior changes in any way, then you are too close. You can safely observe these creatures from a distance without creating a stressful situation.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true,"start":3} -->
<ol start="3"><li>Keep dogs away from moose. Dogs tend to bark at and even run after moose, which can trigger an attack.<br></li><li>Limit observation time. Even if you don’t notice the moose becoming stressed, don’t push your luck. Limit the amount of time you spend observing them.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true,"start":5} -->
<ol start="5"><li>Be patient. If a moose is blocking the road of your path, be patient. They can be slow moving, but you don’t want to trying to hurry them along can be dangerous.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Moose Attack Body Language</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":368,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/moose-4805194_1920-1024x678.jpg" alt="Moose in laying in forest" class="wp-image-368"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While a moose can be unpredictable, their body language will change if they are feeling threatened. A moose will make eye contact, lower their head, lay back their ears, grunt and stomp when they are about to attack. People tend to think of moose as slow-moving creatures, but they can be extremely quick and flexible when necessary. In fact, they are the only species in the deer family that can kick with both the front and back legs in all directions. That means that you can receive a blow even if you approach it from the side. When a moose raises its hackles it is about to charge.<mark class="annotation-text annotation-text-yoast" id="annotation-text-c80bd783-2911-4a05-93c0-24d82224f6ec"></mark> It is also important to keep in mind that all of these cues can happen in a split second. You may not have enough time to observe the moose’s body language and start to retreat, so be careful not to provoke a moose. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>What&nbsp; to Do if a Moose Charges</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Running the is the best thing you can do when a moose charges. If you can, try to put a tree or car between you and the animal as you make your retreat. Typically, once a moose feels that you are a safe distance away, they will stop attacking. If you aren’t able to escape in time, there is a good chance that you will receive a kick from one of their front hooves. If hit, continue to retreat. While it is unusual for a moose to strike repeated blows and engage in a sustained attack, your best line of defense is to get as far away as possible. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It is important to treat local Alaskan wildlife with respect. Not only will this help protect you from a moose attack, but it will also allow the moose to avoid stressful situations. When you do encounter a moose, keep your distance, and immediately retreat if you do see any signs of aggression. While these animals aren’t inherently aggressive, they will attack if they feel threatened or want to protect their young.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-10-08 04:44:08]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/how-to-prevent-moose-attack/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mammal-386740_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/moose-4805194_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wolves-4377376_1920.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[mammal-386740_1920.jpg|moose-4805194_1920.jpg|wolves-4377376_1920.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mammal-386740_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/moose-4805194_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/wolves-4377376_1920.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[367|368|370]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[mammal-386740_1920|moose-4805194_1920|wolves-4377376_1920]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[How to prevent a moose attack||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/mammal-386740_1920.jpg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[375]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[How to Prevent a Bear Attack]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska is home to a diverse population of wildlife that includes both brown (or grizzly) bears and black bears. If you live in Alaska, it can be quite common to encounter one of these majestic and intelligent animals. While they are an exciting sight to see, they also present a real danger and it is important that you take steps to prevent a bear attack and know exactly what to do if you find yourself in a sticky situation. Follow this guide to learn more and protect yourself from a bear attack.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Black Bears</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":379,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/black-bear-750091_1920-1024x768.jpg" alt="Black bear eating in the wild" class="wp-image-379" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Black bears are the most common type of bear and inhabit most of Alaska. While they are called black bears, they can come in different shades of brown, white and black. They tend to have bigger ears, darker colored claws and a brown line with a flatter slope than brown bears. Black bears are also significantly smaller than other species. On average, an adult male will&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>reach 180 to 200 pounds.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Black Bear Behavior</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Black bears tend to be solitary creatures, except during the mating season or in cases of a mother and her cubs. They have a home range that they roam in order to find food and water, but they aren’t territorial and don’t mind coming across other bears and animals in their space. While there have been <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bear_attack#:~:text=The%20number%20of%20black%20bear,to%20serious%20injury%20and%20death.">23 deadly black bear attacks from 1900 to 1980</a>, these animals aren’t considered especially aggressive. Typically, attacks are motivated by hunger, especially in areas where bears have become used to eating human food.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Black Bear Body Language</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Black bears give plenty of warning signs when they are feeling threatened. They will slap the ground, snort air through their nose and snap their teeth together. If this doesn’t work, they will charge and then quickly veer away in a bluff attack. These bears scare easily and don’t want a confrontation. Any aggressive body language is simply meant to scare you off and avoid having to attack.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>How to Survive a Black Bear Attack</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First and foremost, always carry bear pepper spray and have it handy so that you can easily spray a charging bear. Also, remember that black bears aren’t very aggressive and usually bluff an attack just to get you to leave. If you stand your ground, make lots of noise and wave your arms around, you can probably prevent an attack. Never run, climb a tree or play dead. This can provoke an attack and black bears are excellent climbers. In the rare case that you are attacked, fight back by punching it in the nose.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Brown Bears</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":377,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/grizzly-bear-2788682_1920-1024x682.jpg" alt="prevent a brown bear attack" class="wp-image-377" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Unlike black bears, grizzly bears have a muscular hump on their shoulders and shorter, rounder ears. They are also significantly bigger and <a href="http://www.adfg.alaska.gov/index.cfm%3Fadfg=brownbearhunting.main#:~:text=Alaska%20has%20an%20estimated%2030%2C000%20brown%20bears%20statewide.">weigh over a thousand pounds</a>. These bears live throughout Alaska and have a population of over 30,000.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Brown Bear Behavior</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Over the centuries, brown bears evolved and adapted to living in treeless areas. This makes them more aggressive than black bears. They are more likely to stand their ground when they feel threatened. This is especially true when it comes to mothers who are protecting their young. While they aren’t territorial, they will protect food sources.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Brown Bear Body Language&nbsp;</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When it comes to body language black and brown bears send similar signals. Brown bears will also sway their heads, snap their teeth, snort and lay back their ears. The big difference is that black bears are typically bluffing and will run away if you make enough noise. On the other hand, this type of aggressive behavior from a brown bear should be taken seriously. They don’t bluff and they will act on their warning signals.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>How to Survive a Brown Bear Attack</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Remember that brown bears behave differently than black bears. They are much more likely to react even at a greater distance. While bear spray is your best bet, there are some other rules of thumb that will help you survive a brown bear attack.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Brown bears are not great climbers, so if you can make it up a tree, this could provide safe shelter. While you want to run from a black bear, this is not the right move with a brown bear. Despite their size, they are incredibly fast and will certainly give chase. If the bear gets close enough and makes contact, play dead. The vast majority of attacks are defensive in nature. Essentially, they are trying to eliminate the threat and not kill you, which is why playing dead can work. Lay on your stomach and cover the back of your head with your hands. The bear may try to roll you over, so stick out your elbows and use them to remain on your stomach. If the bear is able to flip you, keep rolling until you are able to land back on your stomach.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Try to remain calm and still until the bear stops attacking. Once the bear leaves, continue to play dead for at least 30 minutes before you get up. This will give the bear enough time to get a safe distance away.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Learn the Difference between Black and Brown Bears</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As you can see, the way you should react to an encounter with a bear depends greatly on the type of bear. Black and brown bears have completely different behaviors, which influence how they react to perceived threats and how they defend themselves and their young. It is important to understand the distinguishing features of black and brown bears so that you can quickly identify what you are dealing with and react accordingly. This knowledge can help you avoid confrontations and safely enjoy the Alaskan wilderness.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=375]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bear-2116500_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/grizzly-bear-2788682_1920.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/black-bear-750091_1920.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[bear-2116500_1920.jpg|grizzly-bear-2788682_1920.jpg|black-bear-750091_1920.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bear-2116500_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/grizzly-bear-2788682_1920.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/black-bear-750091_1920.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[381|377|379]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[bear-2116500_1920|grizzly-bear-2788682_1920|black-bear-750091_1920]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[Bear in Alaska||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bear-2116500_1920.jpg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Amy]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Blitchok]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[ablitchok@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[ablitchok]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[387]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Top Ice Cream Destinations In Alaska]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska offers a host of family-friendly activities and restaurants and what's more family-friendly than ice cream? Here is the master list for the best ice cream joints in Alaska coming from ice cream loving Alaskans. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Wild Scoops |Anchorage, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":393,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/d613d7_e03fc2c2cb704c4da9268e895a53f583_mv2_d_1200_1200_s_2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-393"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This unique ice cream shop located in downtown and midtown Anchorage is a classic favorite for all resident Alaskans. Holding true to their name, Wild Scoops offers a variety of uncommon flavors such as Sitka Swirl, Fireweed, and even Spruce Tip. Their menu is ever-changing, always adding new and exciting options to their list. When creating flavors they use all-natural ingredients along with their Alaska themed add-ins, including on their menu vegan and dairy-free alternatives. They are always accepting local produce such as rhubarb and berries which they will trade for pints of ice cream, this means the flavors and produce stay local while supporting the community and bringing people closer together. In addition to cake cones, they also hand-make waffle cones on-site that are very delicious and add to the amazing experience. Another one of their specialties is the Baked Alaska which is a homemade waffle cone filled with the ice cream of your choice and topped with toasted marshmallow meringue. Through this pandemic they have remained open, however, they aren’t allowing in-store seating. You can easily order over the phone((907) 444-0714) or on their website and utilize their curbside pick up. At their Midtown location, they are providing take-out if you prefer. The reviews for Wild Scoops are very satisfactory, the staff is friendly and helpful, the service is efficient and careful and the ice cream is a must-have. Overall, Wild Scoops is a highlight of the dessert scene in Anchorage.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 744-7295, <a href="https://www.wildscoops.com/">Wild Scoops Website</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g60880-d12501334-Reviews-Wild_Scoops-Anchorage_Alaska.html">Reviews for Wild Scoop</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Motley Moo |Anchorage, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":392,"width":307,"height":222,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/3a7c0337efa3ee8d73c02fc0897693daa529a206f1cfd529fb0756a01d47eec8-rimg-w526-h380-gmir.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-392" width="307" height="222"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This new and upcoming sweet stop has been receiving solid reviews from Alaskans all over. Popular for its smooth and creamy ice cream it also boasts of one of the best dairy-free ice creams around. With unique flavor names such as Freckle-Faced Mint and Crude Oil, Motley Moo is definitely a crowd-pleaser. All of their produce and dairy are sourced from Havemeister Dairy right here in Alaska keeping it local and fresh year-round. The owner of Motley Moo, Calesta Ayer was born and raised in Alaska along with her husband and son. With this passion for the community, they have set up a charity fund, “Motley Moo Milk Fund”, and donate as much as they can to families and people in need. They strive to connect local businesses with social responsibility through this fund which they allocate 1% of all of their sales towards. They are open for curbside pickup currently but you can find their amazing ice cream in various other eateries around town such as Moose’s Tooth and 49th State Brewing. Or even better, stop by their scoop shop where you can purchase pint\quart sizes of all of your favorites.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 522-1190, <a href="https://www.motleymoo.com/">Motley Moo Website</a>, <a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/motley-moo-creamery-anchorage">Reviews for Motley Moo</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Woohoo! Ice Cream |Anchorage, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Known for it’s fun and mouth-watering cold treats, Woohoo! Ice Cream also represents Alaska in the 50 Best Ice Cream Parlors in America. They pride themselves on their super-premium ice cream, meaning the fat content is high and the ingredients are of the highest quality. A flourish of organic honey mixed with this ice cream base creates its signature ice cream that is so loved by Alaskans. Some of their more popular flavors include the Maple Butter Pecan, Summer Construction(Rocky Road), and the sweet but spicy Thai Tea flavor. Along with the creamy and magical ice cream they serve, their customer service is also through the roof. Owned by the married couple, Peter and Taian Trujillo-Woo the passion they have for the community and for ice cream simply shine through their smiles and friendly greetings. In response to COVID-19, they have shortened their hours but still are open for takeout or curbside pickup if you’d prefer.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":394,"width":493,"height":490,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/277065826a0f27fa8c9cbdf4f719ec3a.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-394" width="493" height="490"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 351-3087, <a href="http://www.woohooicecream.com/">Woohoo! Website</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g60880-d13820718-r616108684-WooHoo_Ice_Cream-Anchorage_Alaska.html">Reviews for Woohoo!</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Little Millers |Wasilla, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":388,"width":287,"height":431,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/69757194_2520578428005020_9142002988078858240_n.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-388" width="287" height="431"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Soft serve with a twist, seriously. Famous for its flavor burst ice cream cones, Little Millers is a small cafe located in Wasilla. They create the flavor burst by lining the ice cream with a delicious sauce (flavor is optional). You’re left with a colorful and fun treat. It not only has soft serve but also smoothies baked goods and coffee. Even though the pandemic they are still serving takeout as well as opening a drive-thru.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 376-6129, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/littlemillers/">Little Millers Facebook Page</a>, <a href="http://yelp.com/biz/little-millers-ice-cream-express-wasilla">Reviews for Little Millers</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Harbor Street Creamery |Seward, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":399,"width":165,"height":220,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/good-ice-cream.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-399" width="165" height="220"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A quick one-stop-shop that has all of your favorite cold treats! Floats, coffees, smoothies, soft serve, and sundaes are just the tip of the ice cream iceberg here. Even with the seemingly endless amount of options the quality still remains top-notch. It’s a perfect place to stop after fishing or on a hot day. The environment is very welcoming as well and the customer service is exemplary.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 224-8818, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/category/Ice-Cream-Shop/Harbor-Street-Creamery-512488825501602/">Harbor Street Creamery Facebook Page</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g60873-d1121687-Reviews-Harbor_Street_Creamery-Seward_Alaska.html">Reviews for Harbor Street Creamery</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Flagship Creamery |Homer, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Crepes and ice cream are what make this little creamery stand out in Homer, Alaska. They serve the classic flavors with an optional topping of their homemade sauces. As for the crepes you can choose either sweet or salty depending on their daily flavor board. But why choose when you can have both? The Crepe Bomb is an ice cream filled crepe and a popular favorite.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":398,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-1-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-398"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 299-8624, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/flagshipcreamery/menu/?ref=page_internal">Flagship Creamery's Facebook Page</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g31009-d12699677-Reviews-Flagship_Creamery-Homer_Alaska.html">Flagship Creamery Reviews</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>COPPA |Juneau, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":396,"width":264,"height":175,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/coppa-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-396" width="264" height="175"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A must-have if you crave unusual flavors, COPPA is a modern and unique ice cream joint located in Juneau. Black Cod, Blue Cheese, and Spruce Tip have all been past flavors. Along with great ice cream, they also offer salads, sandwiches, and take and bake cinnamon rolls. They boast of great customer service and ambiance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 586-3500, <a href="http://www.coppa.biz/">COPPA Website</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g31020-d4994345-Reviews-Coppa-Juneau_Alaska.html">Reviews for COPPA</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Hot Licks Ice Cream |Fairbanks, Alaska|</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":390,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hot-licks.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-390"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First opening in February of 1986, Hot Licks Ice Cream provides a classic take on ice cream making it a great experience for the whole family. This little stop in Fairbanks offers flavors such as Northern Bluet and Prudhoe some unique flavor names that taste amazing.&nbsp;Be sure to stop by for not only delicious ice cream but a novel experience.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Information: (907) 479-7813, <a href="http://www.hotlicks.net/">Hot Licks Website</a>, <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g60826-d3443867-Reviews-Hot_Licks_Homemade_Ice_Cream-Fairbanks_Alaska.html">Reviews for Hot Licks</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Like this article? Be sure to check out our other ones at <a href="https://akrdy.com/articles/">https://akrdy.com/articles/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=387]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/69757194_2520578428005020_9142002988078858240_n.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/coppa.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hot-licks.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5a31bca77fa5e.image_.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/3a7c0337efa3ee8d73c02fc0897693daa529a206f1cfd529fb0756a01d47eec8-rimg-w526-h380-gmir.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/d613d7_e03fc2c2cb704c4da9268e895a53f583_mv2_d_1200_1200_s_2.png|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/277065826a0f27fa8c9cbdf4f719ec3a.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/coppa-1.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-1.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-1-1.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/good-ice-cream.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[69757194_2520578428005020_9142002988078858240_n.jpg|coppa.jpg|hot-licks.jpg|5a31bca77fa5e.image_.jpg|3a7c0337efa3ee8d73c02fc0897693daa529a206f1cfd529fb0756a01d47eec8-rimg-w526-h380-gmir.jpg|d613d7_e03fc2c2cb704c4da9268e895a53f583_mv2_d_1200_1200_s_2.png|277065826a0f27fa8c9cbdf4f719ec3a.jpg|coppa-1.jpg|download-1.jpg|download-1-1.jpg|good-ice-cream.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/69757194_2520578428005020_9142002988078858240_n.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/coppa.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/hot-licks.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/5a31bca77fa5e.image_.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/3a7c0337efa3ee8d73c02fc0897693daa529a206f1cfd529fb0756a01d47eec8-rimg-w526-h380-gmir.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/d613d7_e03fc2c2cb704c4da9268e895a53f583_mv2_d_1200_1200_s_2.png|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/277065826a0f27fa8c9cbdf4f719ec3a.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/coppa-1.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-1.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/download-1-1.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/good-ice-cream.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[388|389|390|391|392|393|394|396|397|398|399]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[69757194_2520578428005020_9142002988078858240_n|coppa|hot-licks|5a31bca77fa5e.image_|3a7c0337efa3ee8d73c02fc0897693daa529a206f1cfd529fb0756a01d47eec8-rimg-w526-h380-gmir|d613d7_e03fc2c2cb704c4da9268e895a53f583_mv2_d_1200_1200_s_2|277065826a0f27fa8c9cbdf4f719ec3a|coppa-1|download-1|download-1-1|good-ice-cream]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||||||||||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||||||||||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[||||||||||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[402]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Photography In Alaska]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska is full of amazing places and opportunities that allow people to experience the out of the ordinary. What better way to capture Alaska's natural beauty and awe than through photography. I've compiled a list of famous photographers, photography experiences, and some tips on taking photos in Alaska.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Photographers in Alaska</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While there a hundreds of talented and knowledgeable photographers in Alaska, </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Chris Marler Photography</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Chris is a fine art, landscape, and wildlife photographer originally from Boise, Idaho. He took up nature photography as a teenager, and his hobby turned into his career. Chris graduated from the University of Idaho with a degree in computer science, which helped him discover different software and shaped his vision. He retired in 2019 and turned his photography into a full-time career. One of his personal goals is to visit every National Park, and he’s got 32 down with 30 remaining.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/BSw1mJCc05G6mBalFin5vog6uqyrvEMaiNxZyGolJWjtAvh9Dpb35y6eeebcFHyDzh4tRUIFXP5tV6nbdPvj00Tzxsncl7kfwgCxHpuoxPJqEk5B5ItvrRikK78jegLEFu54mke4" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.chrismarlerphotography.com/">https://www.chrismarlerphotography.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Hugh Rose Photography</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A professional photographer located in Fairbanks, Alaska, Hugh Rose has a passion for the Arctic. In his own words, “I find the arctic of Alaska, and it’s diverse flora and fauna to be one of the most interesting and scenically beautiful places on earth and thus an inspirational region for photography.” Hugh loves to get off the beaten path and away from the tourists to take his photos. He has a guide service for others like him who like to experience the raw, natural Alaska.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PTn9FF57YLBIGF62nkIMcTOmjaMHMsRxdpv0VRVo7ar2rP5PiSdthXAYHCmpF09mGN_xZ6MCWgfUDP7GsQc_QIkxUmawzCaACZ5vxpp9_p-AUMAOt-zOhc4XQzXeH4Azok_GewCt" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To purchase his work or learn more about him, you can visit ﻿<a href="https://hughrosephotography.com/">https://hughrosephotography.com</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Tekalnika Photography</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Run by Colorado natives Guy Runco and his wife, Shina duVall, Teklanika Photography provides a beautiful take on nature. The name was inspired by the Teklanika River, the core feeder stream into the Yukon River. A lover of the outdoors, Guy spends hours in nature studying wildlife and capturing breathtaking photos.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/TldtBS9ZaN5aDOONmujA7BiYP15nDhSa5Wu5uHrnqUi_thu-XHWma6k208VtbMUBAyMH8RkSKcFosoWiAJgKSnasSt5L_aHNzIz9x3jpYk3BS6RjTuV72mg0QXvv7NyGU7ndQ3HD" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To purchase Guy’s work or learn more about him you can visit,&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.teklanikaphotography.com/index">https://www.teklanikaphotography.com/index</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Ray Bulson Photography</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":515,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/I0000HT11h4zpIo4.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-515"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.raybulson.com/alaska-fine-art-photos">https://www.raybulson.com/alaska-fine-art-photos</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Photography Charters</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Charters are the perfect way to experience </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.akwildernesscharters.com/photography.htm">https://www.akwildernesscharters.com/photography.htm</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Like this article? Be sure to check out our other ones at <a href="https://akrdy.com/articles/">https://akrdy.com/articles/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=402]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/I0000HT11h4zpIo4.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[I0000HT11h4zpIo4.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/I0000HT11h4zpIo4.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[515]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[I0000HT11h4zpIo4]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[408]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[5 Peaks to Summit Near Anchorage]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There is a reason that people use the term, "mountain top experience." As a hiker, reaching the peak of a mountain is an exhilarating moment that's hard to reproduce anywhere else. The challenge, the views, and the simple knowledge that you've gone as far as you can on a mountain make reaching a peak a worthwhile experience.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In Alaska, the sheer number of peaks surrounding you at any given location can feel overwhelming. It can be hard to know where to start, especially if you are new to hiking. We've narrowed the choice down to five popular hikes, within an hour of Anchorage, that offer beginners a chance to bag their first peak!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Mount Baldy</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate (depending on which route up the mountain you decided to take.) </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: Approximately 3 miles round trip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation gain</strong>: 1512 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: Free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Website: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/mount-baldy-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/mount-baldy-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There is a reason that alltrails.com marks this as "heavily trafficked." It is one of the most popular hikes in the Anchorage area! There are two gates at the end of the Mt Baldy parking lot. Choose the one on the right, as the one on the left is private property.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Early in the hike there are a series of switchbacks that wind through fields which, from the end of June to the middle of July, are covered in wild flowers. As summer gives way to fall, you'll find patches of low-bush blueberries dotting the terrain along the trail.&nbsp; About midway up the mountain you'll face a decision; head straight up, or continue using switchbacks to the peak. As you might imagine, straight up is faster, but more difficult. Trekking poles and good shoes are warranted if you take this avenue and it can be tough on your little hikers or those carrying children. The second option is the longer, but much less steep trail up the back side of the mountain.&nbsp; There is a small sign directing hikers to these switchbacks, so be on the lookout!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Once you've reach the top, taken pictures and patted yourself on the back, it's time to head back. Just like your trip up, you have options heading down. Again, straight down will be the fastest, but most arduous. Be prepare for some sliding and slipping. Trekking poles are extremely helpful! You can also take the switchbacks down and, if you're lucky, sometimes you'll see paragliders using a nearby ridge as a starting point for their lazy trip to the valley below.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":424,"sizeSlug":"large","className":"is-style-default"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-style-default"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1BC481FD-D90A-43C1-A3D7-429BEC69DE49-1024x536.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-424"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Mt Gordon Lyon</strong>s</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 3.5 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 1400 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: $5</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/mt-gordon-lyons">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/mt-gordon-lyons</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Arctic Valley is a great place to begin to learn the ins-and-outs of hiking. The choices for length and difficulty are many and whether or not you decided to climb all the way up the mountains on either side, you'll still be able to see some fantastic views.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>After parking, head towards the little ski lodge in the middle of the valley. From there you'll spot the valley trail. Follow this trail as it slowly winds over streams, through fields of flowers and up to Rendezvous Point, a saddle between Mt Gordon Lyon and Mt Rendezvous. For Gordon-Lyon, head left. The trail is fairly easy to follow. The climb to the peak is moderately difficult, but not excessively steep. It's more of a, "just-keep-putting-one-foot-in-front-of-another" kind of hike. Trekking poles are helpful. At the top you'll be rewarded with views of Denali herself if it's clear!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Heading down can be accomplished by going back the way you came, or ridge walking back towards the parking lot and hiking down the trail right past the research facility that sits above Arctic Valley. Watch out for signs warning you when you've crossed into Military-owned land however!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":447,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/CD2C64CA-BF1E-4DE5-8352-6D20CDC1CC66-1024x627.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-447"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Mt Rendezvous</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 3.5 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation</strong> Gain: 1400 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: $5</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/rendezvous-peak-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/rendezvous-peak-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This mountain has the same starting point as Gordon-Lyons, the beautiful Arctic Valley. The most direct route to the top of Rendezvous is to follow the valley trail back to the saddle and then head right, following the clearly marked trail that runs along the edge of the ridge.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The climb up Rendezvous, like Gordon-Lyons, is moderately difficult. Pace yourself and don't feel bad if you need to stop and catch you breath. (We've all been there!) The trail is well maintained and easy to follow. There is a point when you have the option of continuing the trail down into the valley (called Hanging Valley, if you want another hiking suggestion) behind Rendezvous. Instead of that (unless you're looking for a very long hike), do a little scrambling to climb up to the peak of the mountain.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>From the top you'll be rewarded with fantastic views of Anchorage, the Turnagain Arm, South Fork and the Chugach Mountains. If hiking in the spring, you have the fun option of "glissading" (sliding) down the snowy slopes on the opposite side of the mountain. The serious winter hikers can even buy pants that are designed for this adventurous method of descending! If it's summer time, you can easily spot and follow the trail down as it runs underneath the ski lifts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Blueberry Hill</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 2 miles</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 1128 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: Free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/explore/trail/us/alaska/blueberry-hill">https://www.alltrails.com/explore/trail/us/alaska/blueberry-hill</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a short and sweet peak. The parking is limited, so sometimes is best to plan on an early start to this particular hike. Late spring into early summer provides the best trail conditions, along with the chance to view some gorgeous Alaskan wildflowers. Too early in the season and you'll encounter a lot of very slippery mud as you climb.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Beginning in a birch forest, the trail switchbacks up to the saddle where hikers have the option of heading right or left. For this hike you'll want to head left. That is, head left after you've enjoyed the views of the winding Eagle River, wild lupine, fireweed and (if hiking during the fall) finding handfuls of lowbush blueberries to snack on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The trail is easy to see from the saddle and simple to follow it up to the peak. There are sections where the trail requires some scrambling, but it's minimal. The views from the top showcase Eagle River and the surrounding mountain ranges (including Baldy, if you've hiked that already!) Once satisfied with all the pictures you've taken and after having patted yourself on the back for having bagged another peak, you simply head back down the same way you came up.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":474,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/110575140_10107124248091814_5265756790095911459_o-e1595457807253-1024x555.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-474"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Flattop Mountain</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate (most difficult at the very end)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 3.3 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 1430 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: $5</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/flattop-mountain">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/flattop-mountain</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Another very popular hiking destination is Flattop Mountain. There are a few ways to scale this mountain, but we'll detail the most direct route, up the front.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The hike begins by climbing up a hill named Blueberry Loop - and, as you might imagine, in the fall people frequently leave the trail in order to hunt for nearby&nbsp; blueberries. Once you reach the back of he loop you'll run smack into the base of Flattop mountain.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A clearly marked trail starts the increasingly steep trek up the face of the mountain. Parts of the climb are punctuated by "steps" (if you can call them that after erosion and earthquakes have caused them to lean pretty precariously!) The last push comes after reaching a small saddle and then following the trail up and through a short, steep scramble over boulders! Little hikers might find it challenging, and parents will need to decide if it's doable. But with patience and assistance, many kids have made it up to the flagpole for a celebratory picture!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Keep an eye out for paragliders on clear days as you head back down the mountain (though, maybe not while scrambling down the boulders. : ) Once you reach the junction of Flattop and Blueberry loop, you can continue the loop around the hill and wind you way back to the parking lot.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-07-22 16:27:10]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=408]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/C2B59709-3ACE-43A2-8D6B-58C777526952-scaled.jpeg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/110575140_10107124248091814_5265756790095911459_o-e1595457807253.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[C2B59709-3ACE-43A2-8D6B-58C777526952-scaled.jpeg|110575140_10107124248091814_5265756790095911459_o-e1595457807253.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/C2B59709-3ACE-43A2-8D6B-58C777526952-scaled.jpeg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/110575140_10107124248091814_5265756790095911459_o-e1595457807253.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[431|474]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[C2B59709-3ACE-43A2-8D6B-58C777526952|110575140_10107124248091814_5265756790095911459_o]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[|]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[|]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[|]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/C2B59709-3ACE-43A2-8D6B-58C777526952-scaled.jpeg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Hiking]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Liz]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Snyder]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[lizzybethjane@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[lizzybethjane]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[435]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[5 Stoller-Friendly Hikes Near Anchorage]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For Alaska's littlest hikers (whether in strollers or backpacks) there are a number of trails that families can enjoy together without worrying about elevation gains and difficult terrain. If you have visitors who are unable to complete uphill hiking, these make excellent options that provide exceptional Alaskan views. Here are five easy hikes for families to enjoy together that are within an hour and a half of Anchorage!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Eagle River Nature Center</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: Flat</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: Various; shortest route is .8 miles round trip.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/parks/us/alaska/eagle-river-nature-center">https://www.alltrails.com/parks/us/alaska/eagle-river-nature-center</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is easily one of the most beloved family destination in the Anchorage area, and for good reason. The views are spectacular, the options for length of hike are numerous, and most of the trails are flat and stroller accessible (with all-terrain strollers fairing the best.)&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The most common of these is the Rodak Nature Loop which is an easy walk from the parking lot down to the viewing deck and back. However you can easily venture father back along the old Iditarod trail for a few miles. All the trails are well marked and easy to follow. Wildflowers grow in abundance and there are more than a few fun places for children to climb and explore right off the main trail. During the spring and summer you do need to check at the center for reports regarding bear activity. Keep the bear spray close and the bear bells (or children) loud : )</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":441,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4816-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-441"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Eklutna Lake Bike Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>:&nbsp; Flat</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: In and out for as long as you'd like.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/eklutna-lakeside-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/eklutna-lakeside-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whether you want to hang out by the lake skipping rocks, ride bikes or take strollers along the paved trail, or hike up to a mountain overlook, there are lots of things to keep families busy at Eklutna Lake. During the summer there are even kayak rentals available for those looking for some aquatic adventure!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For families with littles, the paved bike trail that runs along the edge of the lake is perfect for an lovely walk in the summer or fall. You can easily leave the trail at multiple points to go down to the lake and explore. Go as far as you'd like before turning around and heading pack to the parking lot. The full trail is 12 miles one way with some elevation gain starting around mile 10. Whichever direction you are heading, the views can't be beat.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Reflection Lake</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain: </strong>Flat</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 1.1 Mile roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: Free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/reflection-lake-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/reflection-lake-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is another favorite spot for families. At just over a mile, the trail is the perfect length for little legs. Strollers are able to make the loop fairly easily, allowing for a few bumps due to roots and uneven packed earth in places. As it's name implies, the lake is a beautiful, calm body of water. You can spend a lot of time taking pictures of the mountains and their reflected image as you walk. In the wintertime, this lake freezes and the hike can be cut in half if you are willing to walk across the frozen expanse! Be sure to pack bug spray as the mosquitoes love the sitting water of the marsh behind the lake. And while mosquitoes aren't very welcome, the lookout by the marsh provides visitors with opportunities to see beaver, muskrats and moose!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":440,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/A295F230-893F-4F14-BA2B-3DB47FE5DF1D-1024x536.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-440"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Byron Glacier Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 100 ft</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 2 miles</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: Free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Website: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/byron-glacier-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/byron-glacier-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Many people use this trail to hike all the way to the back of the valley and up to the glacier. However, for those not looking for such a strenuous adventure, the first part of the trail is relatively flat and easily navigated. All-terrain strollers can make the trip over the packed earth trail, though there are sections where it's a little bumpy and rocky. Along the way are places to stop and creek stomp in the (chilly) glacial melt and in late summer the path is lined with salmon berries and raspberries!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Once you reach the end of the designated trail the valley opens up and you can explore the rocky terrain and enjoy the beautiful views. Be wary of standing under or climbing on top of snow caves however! These can quickly become unstable, leading to collapse. Stay safe by enjoying the views from a slight distance.&nbsp; Nonetheless, snow itself is lots of fun and there are plenty of snow patches around the valley, even into early July.&nbsp; Snowball fights in July…now who wouldn't love that! Bear spray is warranted as is bug spray, especially during late spring.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":444,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_5026-scaled-e1595449970176-1024x301.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-444"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Powerline Pass</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: Flat (for first few miles)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 1-2 miles for strollers</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/powerline-pass-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/powerline-pass-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Powerline pass provides families with an easily accessible trail near Anchorage with creeks to play in, flowers to view and various options for length of hike. As it's name suggests, the trail runs underneath a powerline which is positioned&nbsp; in the valley between two mountain ranges.&nbsp; If you've hiked Flattop Mountain, you've most likely looked down at this family trail from above. Parking is shared with those hiking either Blueberry Knoll or Flattop.&nbsp; The trail itself is a mix of gravel, boardwalk and packed earth. All-terrain strollers are easy to use for the first mile or so. Again, always pack bear spray and keep your eyes out for other wild life! It can also be windy, so a jacket would be worth having on hand.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-07-22 20:08:17]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=435]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/2FFF5662-BEEC-4907-9B6C-2F6D382E0F97-scaled.jpeg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4816-scaled-e1595448258309.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[2FFF5662-BEEC-4907-9B6C-2F6D382E0F97-scaled.jpeg|IMG_4816-scaled-e1595448258309.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/2FFF5662-BEEC-4907-9B6C-2F6D382E0F97-scaled.jpeg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_4816-scaled-e1595448258309.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[450|441]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[2FFF5662-BEEC-4907-9B6C-2F6D382E0F97|IMG_4816]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[Eklutna Lake|]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[|]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[|]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/2FFF5662-BEEC-4907-9B6C-2F6D382E0F97-scaled.jpeg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Hiking]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Liz]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Snyder]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[lizzybethjane@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[lizzybethjane]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[454]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[5 Moderately Difficult Hikes Near Anchorage]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Not everyone feels the need to reach a mountain peak during every hike, sometimes a fantastic view is plenty. Thankfully, Alaska is full of moderately challenging hikes that will leaving you breathless (because of the beauty, not the hike!) Here are five beautiful hikes that are within an hour and a half of Anchorage.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong><br>Gold Cord Lake Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Easy-Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 1.5 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 482 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/gold-cord-lake">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/gold-cord-lake</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This trail is directly across from the Independence Mine area of Hatcher Pass. You can see the trail head where it starts, direct across the road from the entrance to the upper parking lot. The hike winds across the flat valley floor before snaking up the side of the mountain to a gorgeous glacier lake. The trail runs right along the side of the mountain for a short period of time, so tiny hands might need to be held for a little bit. But the cold mountain water is a welcome relief after this short, steep hike and the views of the Hatcher Pass area can't be beat - like in the photo above. Sometimes some clouds will blow through, but don't worry, they race away as fast as they arrive! This is a fabulous hike for beginning hikers and visiting family and friends.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":469,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9620-1024x672.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-469"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":467,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9618-1024x668.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-467"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Portage Pass Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 4.2 miles</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 1433 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/portage-pass">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/portage-pass</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a beautiful trail to hike at various times of the year. Springtime hiking requires crampons for your shoes as you hike through some snowy parts of the trail, summer hiking gives you gorgeous views of wildflowers covering the mountainside and late August brings an abundance of berries to the bushes along the trail. And no matter which season you choose, the view of Portage Glacier from one direction and of Whittier and the Prince William Sound in the other direction never disappoints.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You can choose to either hike to just the top of the Portage Pass and then back down to your parked car, or you can hike up the pass and then down to the edge of Portage lake before heading back up and over. Trekking polls are helpful, but not necessary.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":455,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/329EC5F4-18EF-48D6-A1F9-BD347243FDD7-1024x536.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-455"/><figcaption>Looking back towards Whittier.<br></figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>West Butte Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Easy-Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 2.3 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 721 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/w-butte-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/w-butte-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you live in the Anchorage area, a trip up "The Butte" is almost a rite of passage for any hiker. This short hike is very well maintained and is great for families with children (as long as they are able to manage stairs and railings on their own.) The views of the valley, Knik Glacier, Knik River and Pioneer Peak are amazing. Don't feel bad if you decided to sit and enjoy the views for a while before heading back down. (Though, if you've forgotten your bug repellent, your stay might be shorter as this hike is on the buggier side : ) This is another hike that is excellent for visiting friends and family.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>Turnagain Arm Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Easy</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: Varies, up to 4.1 miles roundtrip</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 741 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>:&nbsp; <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/turnagain-arm-trail">https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/alaska/turnagain-arm-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This trails runs along the Turnagain arm and is easily accessible from the Seward Highway. It offers beautiful views of the inlet, mountains and highway without a strenuous hike to gain them. You can stay on the trail as long as you'd like before heading back to your car. This is another great trail for family and friends because it gives you a taste of the gorgeous Alaskan vistas without steepness or challenging trail conditions. The trail is especially beautiful in the fall when the birch trees are a vibrant yellow!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One note: This trail is known for it's wildlife encounters. Normally you'll&nbsp; see dale sheep, marmots, and bald eagles. But sometimes, you might run across evidence of bears…meaning it's vital to come prepared with bear spray and bear bells. Stay in a large group and make lots of noise!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3><strong>April Bowl Trail</strong></h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Difficulty</strong>: Easy-Moderate</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 2.2 miles round trip (or less, if you stop at the lake)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Elevation Gain</strong>: 856 feet</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://www.alaska.org/detail/hatch-peak-april-bowl-trail">https://www.alaska.org/detail/hatch-peak-april-bowl-trail</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is another trail in the Hatcher Pass area. Finding the trailhead for this hike was more difficult than I imagined. If you park in the lot for Summit Lake, the trail begins directly behind you on the steep hill leading up to the April Bowl. In the summer the trail may be heavily trafficked, so finding it might be as easy as looking for where other people are headed! The trail is a steep set of switchbacks until you reach the lake. You have the option to stop here and enjoy the amazing views or you can continue up along the ridge that surrounds the lake. At the very top of the ridge is Hatch Peak - so if you feel like it, you can easily cross another mountain top off your list! Trekking poles are helpful, but not necessary for most hikers.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":459,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/2B2BFB54-8ACA-4783-8F92-60F099DB12CD-1024x536.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-459"/><figcaption>From the Top of Hatch Peak, past the April Bowl.<br></figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2020-07-22 21:57:11]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=454]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_7154-scaled.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9618-scaled.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9620-scaled.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[IMG_7154-scaled.jpg|IMG_9618-scaled.jpg|IMG_9620-scaled.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_7154-scaled.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9618-scaled.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_9620-scaled.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[461|467|469]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[IMG_7154|IMG_9618|IMG_9620]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[View from Gold Cord Lake||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[View of Valley From Gold Cord Lake||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/IMG_7154-scaled.jpg]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Hiking]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Liz]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Snyder]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[lizzybethjane@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[lizzybethjane]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[480]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[5 Berry Picking Spots near Anchorage]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>With berry season upon us, it's a good idea to have a few places that you can depend on to have a good supplies of berries! Before heading out, take a little time to read up on the different types of berries and some general information about them. <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.alaska.org/advice/berry-picking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">This site</a> provides a good summary.  </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Foraging is like an unofficial sport here in the last frontier, and there are people who will methodically pick for hours, patiently filling buckets with nature's bounty. But this means that sometimes the place that you were hoping to clear is already empty due to the hard work of another ambitious person. So here are five different places that have ample amount of berries…hopefully enough to go around.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":493,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/D876D83E-918A-40EF-A9C8-6FEE1C687BF6-e1596565669522-1024x627.jpeg" alt="lizandpaulsnyder.com" class="wp-image-493"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Mile High Saddle, Eagle River</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Type of berry</strong>: Lowbush blueberry, crow berries</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Mile High is a great place to hunt for blue berries. Because it takes a rather steep hike up through the woods to reach it, many berry pickers decide not to hunt there. Which means that it's perfect for the more adventurous foragers. Because of it's elevation, the berries might be a week behind those growing at lower altitudes. By early August they should be ready though! You can start hunting right off the trail leading into the saddle and just go where ever the berries take you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Winner Creek Trail, Girdwood</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Type of berry</strong>: High bush blueberry</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: free</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Starting at the trailhead located behind the Alyeska Tram, follow the Winner Creek path for a few miles until you find yourself at an old mining bridge. This bridge, which spans the turbulent creek below, is large and well used by hikers. Parents will need to do a quick risk assessment regarding the safety of going across, but with older children a firm handhold&nbsp; and a slow pace is usually all that is warranted when crossing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On the other side of the creek is a clearing that is covered with bushes. Blueberry bushes, to be precise. With a little exploring, you can often find a whole bush that has been untouched by other foragers. Be careful walking in the forest however. The ground looks firm but can often be just a mossy covering over fallen branches. Walk carefully, stay within eye-sight of other pickers and have bear bells on and jingling. Humans aren't the only ones who love these berries! However, the Winner Creek area is full of berry producing bushes…so there is a good chance that any bears in the area have found a place far away from people.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Girdwood has a very popular blueberry festival most years, which is when you can expect lots of people to descend upon the hills and forests around the town. My advice is to go berry-picking a few days before the festival, just to beat the crowds : )</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":490,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_8944-819x1024.jpg" alt="lizandpaulsnyder.com" class="wp-image-490"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Arctic Valley, Eagle River</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Type of berry</strong>: Low-bush blueberry, low-bush cranberry, crow berry</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: 5 dollars</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a very popular place for berry pickers, with good reason. Starting at the beginning of August, most of the slopes leading down to the valley have large patches of berries scattered across them. A good rule of thumb, when looking for a place to hike towards, is to take a moment and look at where other people are hunkered down. While you don't want to go right on top of them, chances are good that there are more berries in that vicinity. If you ever go hiking in Arctic Valley during the very end of July and beginning of August, keep your eyes out and remember where you saw the most people gathered.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You'll find the low-bush cranberries closest to the creek that runs through the valley.&nbsp; These extremely tart little gems are easily frozen and make great additions to fruit crumbles, pies and thanksgiving day stuffing. I know this from experience : )</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Hatcher Pass, Palmer</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Type of berry</strong>: low-bush blueberry</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Parking</strong>: free (on pull outs along the road.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Due to the higher elevation, these berries are usually ripe in mid-end of August. If you reach the Hatcher pass summit, instead of turning around and heading back, continue heading west on Fishhook -Willow rd, past summit lake and on down the other side of the pass. There are numerous pull-outs along this road that you can park at. Like Arctic Valley, the best way to find a place to pick is to look for other people and head in that direction. Though you can expect to find blue-berries pretty much anywhere along the slopes on either side of the road, its just easier to be a copycat until you get a feel for the area. Be forewarned however, once you start, it's hard to stop! The scenery is gorgeous and&nbsp; the berries are nearly unending. But once you've filled your bucket, head back up the way that you came and head home to look up recipes for your haul!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":491,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_E9577-1024x681.jpg" alt="lizandpaulsnyder.com" class="wp-image-491"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Portage Pass Trail, Whittier</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Type of berry</strong>: Salmon berries</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is definitely a hit-or-miss berry excursion. But if your timing is right (around the middle of July), you can find some amazingly delicious salmonberries.&nbsp; The instructions are pretty simple, just head up the Portage Pass trail and keep your eyes glued to the bushes on either side of the trail. If you are lucky, they'll be full of these beautiful, juicy gems. My advice would be to plan a hike up the pass anyway, and just keep your fingers crossed that you'll be there right when the berries begin to ripen and before anyone else has discovered them : )</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you head to Whittier to fish for salmon, there is a good chance you'll also be near to some berry picking spots. Just keep your eyes open! Maybe you'll head home with two parts of you dinner taken care of!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Happy hunting!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=480]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Living in Alaska>Getting Outdoors>Hiking]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[Liz]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[Snyder]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[lizzybethjane@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[lizzybethjane]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[498]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[5 Family-Friendly Activities in Alaska]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whether you're just visiting or moving here permanently Alaska has so many great options for families with children of all ages. Here are some of the top family-friendly activities you and your loved ones can do while in Alaska.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Anchorage Museum</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/hLVvBzRZycevjz_ZWGhTRY_d8lKNLrkOVvxO7D4GPkz2h-KdPfdgjX2JwmHyesPSmJ-nOuz_7YpHDjKSM7unbyoAjscA0YG0Yc1nLQUbY6Uckt0OQkOTBHKcpQ0G2kSz1YMjNnMH" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Anchorage Museum is a great activity for a rainy (or more commonly in Alaska, snowy) day. It has so much to offer for all ages. One of its permanent exhibitions, Art of the North, showcases the beauty of Alaska through different artist’s portrayal. It features many indigenous arts from the villages and native people, such as sculptures, woven fabrics, and photography which provide insight into the heritage of Alaska. Along with this, you can also experience some classical paintings of some of the most prestigious landmarks. For younger children, they also have an interactive area in which children are given the opportunity to explore and learn about Alaska’s weather, cool scientific phenomenons, and even some wildlife. In addition to these, they also host traveling exhibitions that rotate every few months, providing new learning experiences all year round.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information, you can visit, <a href="https://www.anchoragemuseum.org/">https://www.anchoragemuseum.org/</a> or call 907-929-9200</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Eagle River Nature Center</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Looking for a scenic, easy hike for the entire family? Well, look no further than Eagle River Nature Center. From a stroller accessible trail to amazing outlooks and overviews, its the perfect family outing. Before you start on the trail you can visit the lodge, which is a great place to learn a little about the wildlife in that area, through touching polar bear fur or reading cool facts about animals. Outside of the lodge, there is an outdoor eating area, a perfect place to enjoy a packed lunch after the hike. The trail is full of plaques and signs teaching about the wildlife and vegetation in the area. All in all, a trip to the Eagle River Nature Center never disappoints and is a must-see in Alaska.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":499,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_0170-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-499"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information, you can visit <a href="https://www.ernc.org/">https://www.ernc.org/</a> or call 907-694-2108</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Wildlife Conservation Center</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"left","id":500,"width":292,"height":412,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MBN-Alaska-Wildlife-Conservation-Bear-Viewing.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-500" width="292" height="412"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A unique Alaskan experience for all ages! Wanting to see some Alaskan animals but haven't the chance yet? Well, the Wildlife Conservation Center is a great place to see moose, bears, musk ox, and many more, up close and in their natural habitat. The trip offers not only an unforgettable wildlife encounter but also a learning experience about all of the creatures of Alaska, where they live and how they survive. It is located past Girdwood so it's a bit of a drive from Anchorage but it's one you won't regret. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information, you can visit <a href="https://www.alaskawildlife.org/">https://www.alaskawildlife.org/</a> or call (907) 783-0058</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Alaska Railroad</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","width":306,"height":241} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/DDAPqVrPHy-OCQorwvlbql14w0DWCFzGcwTW6N1tEFYAQXAvPXLOLi8Q1k65Kk9PL387j2AmaxrbkaORZdn3IG26v_CmSNrxCcnAPcNzUACPY6CKDiZ8K9KwSKRcrdSvt2AFu-Cz" alt="" width="306" height="241"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>With a main line that stretches from Fairbanks to Seward (470 miles), The Alaska Railroad is a perfect way to see all of the beautiful scenery Alaska has to offer via a comfortable and accessible transport. Aside from carrying large freight and hosting events, the railroad also has arranged day trips. The most popular ride, “Coastal Classic Train” will take you along the Turnagain Arm, displaying an amazing view of the bay. It will arrive in Seward late morning, leaving you till 6 pm to explore all that the city has to offer.&nbsp;While the fare is a bit pricey it promises to be a rewarding experience with lasting memories.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><br>For more information, you can visit <a href="https://www.alaskarailroad.com/">https://www.alaskarailroad.com/</a> or call (907) 265-2300</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Alaska Zoo</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Alaska Zoo is a nonprofit working to promote the conservation of the arctic and its wildlife. It hosts over 100 different types of animals across 25 acres. While some are native Alaskan wildlife, they also have exotic animals from all around the world. Since it is a nonprofit the zoo does not receive any state or city funding and relies solely on the profit it brings in to care for the animals. This epidemic has affected the Alaska Zoo greatly so a visit here would not only be a fun family outing but help towards a greater cause. All indoor exhibits are currently closed however you can still visit the gift shop (with a mask on of course).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":501,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/OTES3YEC2VD4BJKSV5CBK34IWU.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-501"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information, you can visit <a href="https://www.alaskazoo.org/">https://www.alaskazoo.org/</a> or call (907) 346-2133</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Like this article? Be sure to check out our other ones at <a href="https://akrdy.com/articles/">https://akrdy.com/articles/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=498]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_0170.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MBN-Alaska-Wildlife-Conservation-Bear-Viewing.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/OTES3YEC2VD4BJKSV5CBK34IWU.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[IMG_0170.jpg|MBN-Alaska-Wildlife-Conservation-Bear-Viewing.jpg|OTES3YEC2VD4BJKSV5CBK34IWU.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_0170.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MBN-Alaska-Wildlife-Conservation-Bear-Viewing.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/OTES3YEC2VD4BJKSV5CBK34IWU.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[499|500|501]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[IMG_0170|MBN-Alaska-Wildlife-Conservation-Bear-Viewing|OTES3YEC2VD4BJKSV5CBK34IWU]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[503]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Top 5 Alaskan Clothing Brands]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Moving to Alaska but don’t know what to expect? Well here are the top 5 clothing brands in Alaska that will have you looking like a local.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Xtra Tuf</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The weather in Alaska is pretty unpredictable, but you can be prepared for anything with a solid pair of XTRA TUFs. These water-proof boots allow you to do almost anything without having to worry about the muck or mud! Some boots even have cute and unique designs so you can be stylish and weatherproof. All in all, every Alaskan could use a pair of XTRA TUFs. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":509,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_2400x-1-1024x633.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-509"/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Popular Item:</strong> All-Purpose, Water-proof Boots</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $$-$$$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reviews:</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“I purchased my Xtratuf boots for a small ship cruise in Alaska. I used them several times for small skiff rides and for wading in the water during shore walks. They fit incredibly well and kept my feet warm and dry. All the crew on the ship also wore Xtratuf boots, so I know they have to be good. Looking forward to using them again.” Debra B.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“These boots crush anything in their path, all while keeping the feet dry and comfortable! These boots will be in it for the long haul, and always something I can rely on. The fit is spot on and the look is something I always get compliments on” - Megan O.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information or to purchase their boots, you can visit <a href="https://www.xtratuf.com/">https://www.xtratuf.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Ak Starfish Co</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alaska owned and made, AK Starfish Co. is a fun, fashionable way to support a local business. Most known for their stylish hoodies, zip-up jackets, and hats, these clothes are a perfect way to show off your Alaskan pride. The founder, Marci Nelson is a 3rd generation Alaskan who has spent her entire life exploring Alaska’s natural beauty. In fact, her first-ever design came from a photograph of a starfish in Sadie Cove she took. It's a great way to show off your style while supporting a local business.   </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","width":258,"height":344} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/5L_SYbA5AEdtPh2DT5X0fnDV4J-yRWkndz32hr1qzojerKVKrCH7mr3Sr2AYTU1tBKxF6ih-I0kgyINRMpBpTZ0kQXWJ1eseaMp12PUkXtOTwdyb8QJbSQYjmBaJoM2g_XecfNQB" alt="" width="258" height="344"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Popular Item: </strong>Hoodies and Hats</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reviews:</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Amazing service and quality of the clothing! I love shopping here and knowing I’m supporting local Alaskans.” - Paisley P.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><br>“Marci Nelson creates a wonderful atmosphere for all of her Ak Starfish locations! The hoodies are so soft and durable, not to mention they don't shrink!! Her boutique line is very unique and like no other boutique you will find in Alaska. They also carry tons of Alaskan designed jewelry, stickers, food, cookbooks, and greeting cards!”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information or to purchase their clothing, you can visit <a href="https://www.akstarfish.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.akstarfish.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Alaska Chicks </h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Vintage with a twist, ‘Alaska Chicks’ hoodies are a staple here in Alaska. Their clothes are warm and comfortable perfect for the chilly Alaskan winters. And they don't just sell hoodies but gloves, beanies, and leggings, all of which have great reviews from customers. So if you're looking for a gift for your grandma, mom, or daughter that will be used and loved, Alaska Chicks is the place to go. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/mjIH-xndXj8QCxl-kLKUnYMg66QAqwVFW4NyNLbGjErw-Q450BoUpwf5N3-BbEnqSK_xd6ZfBlDJ8tv4ubwQkP22qFXa6YNr9wSgFZNtm-9v5sdgsZMvcjLliQVGbtLJB3IwKoN6" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Popular Item: </strong>Hoodies</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Cost</strong>: $$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reviews</strong>:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“This is my all-time favorite hoodie. Love the style the fabric, and the length. I have two, and ordered one for my daughter who was trying to steal one of mine!” - Donna B.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“I am in love with this hoodie. This is my second one and I've gotten so many compliments, it’s crazy! I love the fabric and how well it washes up and holds its shape. Perfect fitting and just the correct length for wearing with everything from jeans to leggings!” - Brandy B.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information or to their purchase their clothing, you can visit <a href="https://alaskachicks.com/">https://alaskachicks.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Carhartt</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whether you’re fishing, hiking, camping or just enjoying nature you’ll need durable clothing to get you through all of it. Carhartt, most known for their tough, weather-proof outerwear is the perfect option for the entire family when exploring the great Alaskan outdoors.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"right","id":505,"width":367,"height":551,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img src="https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/4f3f661753bc15f389d4cf56afbc0666.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-505" width="367" height="551"/></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Popular Item: </strong>Overalls, Men’s Coats</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Cost:</strong> $$-$$$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reviews</strong>:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“First thing that comes to mind when I hear this brand is "DURABILITY.” -Rodrigo T.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Great, long-lasting, well designed, and functional clothing.” -Anja F.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more information or to purchase their clothing, you can visit <a href="https://www.carhartt.com/">https://www.carhartt.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Copper River Fleece</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This Alaskan clothing company prides themselves on their unique clothing that showcases the native culture here in Alaska. They're based in Cordova, a small village, and love to use the nature surrounding them in their designs. Tested and approved by hunters, fishermen, and just Alaskans themselves Copper River Fleece has outstanding reviews for durability and longevity. They sell jackets, coats, hats, and all sorts of wearable, fun designs for all ages. Plus, everything is made and designed in the USA! </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/4rwJn8wZ4GKjFmLfl7TZiMTm888MRKo3fmXrCnCPLE93ORiyv99TugjjpPJDa1ENUIcb_USzYGnBmad-XC6K4LXT9KHsOJx5VzPheVBXRU-DdktQBH9pLrxL-mSXEJhDhLz1uu8T" alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Popular Item:</strong> Lined Jackets</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Cost: </strong>$$$</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reviews:</strong> </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Copper River Fleece jackets are beautiful, stylish, lightweight (but warm), wind-resistant, well made, and they fit well.&nbsp; They are quality.&nbsp; I bought my first jacket a couple of years ago and now have four of them.” - Bonnie T.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“We have purchased jackets for the kids for multiple years. Such an amazing product!” -Mike P.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><br>For more information or to purchase their clothing, you can visit <a href="https://www.copperriverfleece.com/">https://www.copperriverfleece.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Loved this article? Check out our others at <a href="https://akrdy.com/articles/">https://akrdy.com/articles/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>**reviews were found at yelp.com or at company website**</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[1970-01-01 00:00:00]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/?p=503]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/4f3f661753bc15f389d4cf56afbc0666.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_180x.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_2400x.jpg|https://akrdy.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_2400x-1.jpg]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[4f3f661753bc15f389d4cf56afbc0666.jpg|22490-CTM_8_180x.jpg|22490-CTM_8_2400x.jpg|22490-CTM_8_2400x-1.jpg]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/4f3f661753bc15f389d4cf56afbc0666.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_180x.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_2400x.jpg|/chroot/home/a100bb6c/akrdy.com/html/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/22490-CTM_8_2400x-1.jpg]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[505|507|508|509]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[4f3f661753bc15f389d4cf56afbc0666|22490-CTM_8_180x|22490-CTM_8_2400x|22490-CTM_8_2400x-1]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[|||]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[|||]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[|||]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[jonesgirl1470]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[862]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Designing a Shared Workspace]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2019-05-20 06:51:31]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/designing-a-shared-workspace/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[christopherjones2621@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[admin]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[863]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Better Living through Design]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2019-05-20 07:01:23]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/better-living-through-design/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[christopherjones2621@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[admin]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[864]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[So you want to be a furniture maker?]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->

Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.

<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2019-05-20 07:02:17]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/so-you-want-to-be-a-furniture-maker/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[christopherjones2621@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[admin]]></authorusername>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[869]]></id>
		<title><![CDATA[Hello world!]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[				Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!		]]></content>
		<excerpt><![CDATA[]]></excerpt>
		<date><![CDATA[2017-03-09 03:18:12]]></date>
		<posttype><![CDATA[post]]></posttype>
		<permalink><![CDATA[https://akrdy.com/hello-world-2/]]></permalink>
		<imageurl><![CDATA[]]></imageurl>
		<imagefilename><![CDATA[]]></imagefilename>
		<imagepath><![CDATA[]]></imagepath>
		<imageid><![CDATA[]]></imageid>
		<imagetitle><![CDATA[]]></imagetitle>
		<imagecaption><![CDATA[]]></imagecaption>
		<imagedescription><![CDATA[]]></imagedescription>
		<imagealttext><![CDATA[]]></imagealttext>
		<imagefeatured><![CDATA[]]></imagefeatured>
		<categories><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></categories>
		<tags><![CDATA[]]></tags>
		<authorfirstname><![CDATA[]]></authorfirstname>
		<authorlastname><![CDATA[]]></authorlastname>
		<authoremail><![CDATA[christopherjones2621@gmail.com]]></authoremail>
		<authorusername><![CDATA[admin]]></authorusername>
	</node>
</data>
